so I was I was a a scrum what was that
called I was uh like a scum scum Breer
no scrum breaker scrum breaker okay so I
went in and like we should do this and
like the whole scrum team is like we
hate you so I was I was the scrum
breaker
[Music]
what's up everybody this is techno geek
from the ctbb Pod so we have a really
exciting feature that we are going to be
rolling out at the drop of this episode
it is our Discord community so we are
going to be emphasizing a lot of really
cool exciting exclusive features within
the Discord Community we'd love to
interact with the people who listen to
our pod and love our pod if you want to
chat with other hackers you want to
discuss bugs um you know we're hoping to
have the guests in there as well
although I don't know if they they will
answer questions so just you know don't
ping them and stuff but uh you know we
we're hoping to have a lot of really
awesome people in there to just come
hang out and build an awesome community
so if that sounds like something that's
interesting to you uh you can go to ctbb
Dosh showd Discord and that will take
you right to the Discord server join
invite link um we will also be rolling
out a couple paid premium tiers so if
you want to financially help support the
pod uh that would be amazing it would
help pay our editors it would help us
make better content for you and uh yeah
that's going to have some exclusive
stuff that comes with it like amas and
masterclass sessions and some exclusive
you know we're going to show some
unredacted bugs stuff like that so if
that sounds like something that's
interesting to you uh let us know and uh
you know come join our Discord Community
again that's ctbb Dosh show Discord and
you can join the community hoping to see
you there peace all right dude fron
we're rolling welcome to the podcast man
thank you so much thanks for inviting me
of course and and so actually before we
jump into this episode I've got to
highlight what the heck this thing is
behind you um there's like a it looks
like it's like a a framed poster of you
with a shell on Google is that exactly
what that is yeah it is it's it's from
2014 I think 2014 are you kidding me
holy crap no yeah yeah 14 yeah yeah were
you born then you shut I was I was I
that's the year I graduated high school
actually yeah no it's uh I think it was
from an xxe if I recall it correctly wow
dude that's nuts so he's just got like
Etsy password on from a Google box on
the wall behind him that's pretty
freaking leap that's all right guys so
as as we often do when we start off the
critical thinking podcast I'm gonna have
to go into Justin story time a little
bit okay so Justin story time is this I
I was at my this the setting was this
Justin was a new a new bug Bounty Hunter
and I had just weasel my way into my
first live hacking event okay um and I
had I I had I was very nervous I was the
plus one of a plus one and uh it was
amazing to get to see all of these
hackers that I um you know had respected
for so long uh but there was one guy in
particular you may be able to guess who
that I had not gone and talked to
because I was just too nervous I was too
nervous man I was like there's no way I
can go up and talk to fron Rosen and I
was talking to my wife Mariah and I was
like listen fron is like a legend like I
can't I can't go up and talk to him and
she's like Justin you're at this live
hacking event you have to go up and talk
to him and at at that event you had
found a crazy bug um with with uh you
know an S3 bucket you know pulling stuff
in and stuff like that um and so I went
up and talked to you and you were so
kind to explain the whole bug to me and
just chat and that was my my first you
know Fanboy moment where I was like wait
a second fron is a real human what's up
with that so wow yeah oh that's amazing
yeah you know normally they say don't
meet your Heroes but I must say fron you
did not disappoint so that's awesome
that's awesome yeah so there's your
little there's your little flattering
intro um for those of you that don't
know frons um fron is a legend a a
hacker a uh a bug Bounty OG um and dude
I'm looking at this this this plan that
we have for this episode and it's so
long I'm not even sure we're going to be
able to get through all this because
there's just so much good content that
you've put out um so thank you for that
but before we get into all that let's go
ahead and talk about how you got into BG
bounty in the first place because you
you got in when it was really early on
the scene and give us a little career
walk through that brought you to the
point where you could do bug Bounty sure
I think I mean initially everything
started off as hiring two young people
uh to my company as developers and these
two young guys uh Matias Carlson and
Freddy K Ru uh they were lurking always
inside in a corner in the office doing
stuff together always and and you you
didn't figure like you couldn't really
understand what they were doing but but
when you started talking with them you
realized like they were probably like AR
spoofing the whole office oh my gosh
that's hilarious okay so I'm going to
pause you really quickly there so you
were you at this point you were already
an entrepreneur so you started you know
you had already started your company
yeah yeah so I can start when when I was
born no just no no so I take us back
yeah exactly take us back no so I I
started as a developer like super early
on and then uh I I built a company
together with the with a business
partner of mine and we hired Frederick
and and Matias and at that time I I
wasn't into hacking I I knew that like
sanitize your inputs that was that was
basically the sure sure the the idea
that I that I knew was was something in
in regards to security uh but this was
very timed also because like this was
200 I think 10 or 11 or something and
and uh I I got curious on what they were
doing and at some point they told us
that they were planning on building like
a company security like a security
company automating security issues so we
were pretty interested in that and we
started talking more deep around like
what would you do what like what is the
product and we kind of realized uh early
on that we could do this together uh
especially because we saw a need for it
in terms of what we were building we
were building like e-commerce websites
and and CMS websites and stuff so we we
then created
detectify and uh and at that point just
when we got started the bug Bounty scene
uh basically was
initiated so it started with like Milla
and I think it was payal and Google and
I think Facebook was early on as well
and then you had you had like like
Russian things as well and and some uh
what what was it there was something
else also that was like super early on I
think eBay was early on as well like
there was a few of those that that
started uh and and you you basically had
like a a way to do like research on a
huge amount of surface like you could
test a bunch of things on on this attack
surface and so that was very helpful in
like getting to understand what they
were looking for but because now you
didn't have to like hide or simulate
fake things you could literally like
focus on on looking for real bugs so
that got me curious on like what should
I start with and I think they they
basically showed me a bunch of xss
things and and that that's where I like
started off and uh and played like xss
was my you know where I was born sure
and then and then it grew from there uh
so I think that was I think it was very
helpful for me to have people next to me
that I could ask and also to to you know
whenever I didn't know anything I could
just ask them and and then I could play
myself and then I could come back and
like get that feedback this is so
awesome because you you you you were in
a position of you know owning this
company or whatever and you hire Matias
I didn't know that that was actually how
you you met Matias in the first place
and then you're willing you know you're
willing and engaged at a level where you
know you can see like hey what are you
doing and then you start this company
with them and it it just shows this
really you know learner mentality and
Matias is like absolutely you know
Matias is Young at this point right yeah
yeah I think they were they were drop
offs from from the University I think
there was like they were like 18 or 19
even that wow they were really young
yeah yeah absolutely and and they they
came basically in and and like they were
they were okay developers but they were
much better when it come to like
security and and security related things
that's when when they were like shining
in terms of skills yeah so we felt that
like it's much better for you to like
focus on those things than you know
making an integration with an invoice
provider like please stop writing code
yeah yeah yeah no not really like write
other code that it's like much more fun
to like no that's that's great I I I've
been meaning to get Matias on the podt
as well so I think I'm gonna send him a
message right after this episode because
I'd love to hear his origin story as
well and his side of the situation where
he's like so there's this guy and he
hired me onto this company and then he's
like why are you ARP spoofing the whole
office you know like I I love that he's
like he probably has a totally different
story he's like no wasn't HED
I I into this company show up on day I
didn't get paid yeah right right
exactly okay so so that that's really
interesting to to hear that that um that
like shift so you were basically just
doing entirely like software development
when you learned about like the security
side of it what sort of peak your
interest to like make that pivot that
like really Drew you towards security
cuz I imagine like if you're doing a lot
of software development and stuff you
probably could have just kept doing that
and not made made a switch into security
so what what was that like draw I think
I I think so I've been like I I was
building you know systems like you you
you you say you're building a system but
like what is a system in in in reality
but I was always like as a developer I
always triy to like oh I can reuse this
I need to build this like modular and
and all these things so I was always
curious on how others were doing it and
this was like I've realized this
probably now after like 14 years but I I
kind of know it like through the whole
time but like I'm I'm super curious on
how other people thought about problems
and issues and I've I've always like
I've almost made it a a challenge to
myself to write like pseudo code of how
something is implemented so I can make a
black box a white box right right uh
just because that's the way I understand
how they thought about things and also
that's how you find that specific little
if statement that they forgot about sure
sure and I think I think that was that
was the point where I realized that I
could do this on other companies and
nobody will like get me into trouble and
I can just you know start poking at them
and see what's what what will happen and
I think that was that was something that
i' like I can do this and also get paid
like this was something I was poking at
before you know just figuring out how
stuff worked
um and now I could do it help other
companies and also you know get paid for
it yeah so I think that was that was the
trigger to like okay I can actually gain
knowledge by doing this and also I have
like a side effect of I can actually you
know make make money for it yeah
absolutely and and I think go go ahead
no no and I think what what happened in
the beginning also when we started with
the bug Bounty was like those those
money came in to our company so we could
fund you know
this company like start these other
companies so it kind of it it was like a
very like a beautiful environment of
like we get to poke on other companies
and that creates other company and it's
like it was a very nice you know
circling effect of of of hunting for
bugs and and you see this a lot with
with bug Bounty origin companies right
like in the beginning when you're trying
to like make ends meet and stuff like
Bounty your own as into think that
provides launching for um you know bug
bounty hunters to uh become
entrepreneurs in that context for sure
there there are many that that has like
popped up yeah yeah and I've got i' I
actually was just speaking to another
one this morning who we'll have on the
Pod so there's definitely some that's
one of the things I'm really interested
in is bug Bounty plus entrepreneurship
so we'll definitely cover more of that
later and I've actually got a section on
this doc if we get through all of it to
to pick your brain a little bit more
about that um but I think you said a
really interesting thing relating to how
you think about hacking which was that
you try to write pseudo code so that you
can kind of understand how the
developers you know would have would
have written this code and turn it you
know from a black box into a white box
um and i' I kind of saw this when we
were collaborating at the last life
hacking event we were at um and and you
did get small indicators and that like
this indicator confirms that they've
done something like this because if this
doesn't happen then and and it turns
almost into like a game where you can
like I'm gonna guess what happens if I
do this I'm gonna get an error and I'm
like yes I'm getting an error okay then
I know that they've done this and that
yeah exactly like that yeah that that's
that's and I think that's probably one
of the things that makes you such a good
uh exploit exploiter exploitation you
know like I I I don't know the I don't
know the actual word but um you know
someone who's really able to take an
issue and just poke poke poke poke poke
poke poke until you turn it into a crazy
vulnerability um so that's that's
definitely a cool tip for anybody who
has that sort of developer like brain to
kind of you know really be intentional
about theor because I think to some
degree we're all doing this a little bit
when we're hacking but I think if you
take that extra step and really start
thinking in the Forefront of your brain
hey how did they write this how is this
how can I confirm this you know what
little errors might tell me whether it's
this or that um you can flesh it out a
lot more and it's the same thing like
when when you've done it with one place
and they have done you know a similar
thing somewhere else yeah then you can
like start comparing them and like okay
but it behaves differently there and
like you can so as soon as you've done
that for like one code block you can see
other implementations in the same
company if they done like you've done a
mistake on one like that that happens a
lot like there's one single thing that
that makes break yeah sorry Joe yeah no
no absolutely I mean there's almost like
two different buckets of of this type of
stuff when you're doing testing where um
like the cat
just yeah he's part of the show too um
yeah but there's almost like two buckets
where like uh you you can there's like
lots of like almost totally like out of
left field type of stuff where you'll
test you be like maybe they did this
maybe they did that they did that like
you never know maybe maybe they made
this weird mistake like I saw this
somewhere else and then there's the very
like logical approach where you think
about it so sort of basically as if
you're one of the developers or you're
coming from the developers perspective
which is you know you know some of the
technologies that they're using you know
some of the common mistakes that happen
within those languages and those
Technologies and so you can sort of
piece things together you can try things
that are a little more targeted towards
like say you're testing you know a Java
application you're going to test stuff
that's similar to spring or you know
you're going to be testing for like Java
specific things instead of like Ruby
issues or JavaScript issues and that
type of testing like it's not to say
that if you test a ruby issue on a Java
stack that like maybe there's something
further down the line that might pop and
you know but often times having that
context as like a developer is really
really useful because you have that like
that background of like this is
something weird that they might have
done yeah and I would say one one of the
things you're mentioning there is like
like I don't know why I think people are
talking about it in a different context
but like typing is like one of the most
one of the best things and one of the
worst things in combination that you can
use like that's one of our biggest tools
that we have is is when like for example
when you have PHP you don't have typing
so that's where what you have there is
like then you can start figuring out
where they screwed up and thought it was
an in but it's a string and and in other
languages it's like just because you
have the typing errors you can start
fussing you know variables that didn't
exist because you're getting a typing
error and so like when you think about
it like that's that's one of my best
Clues there's you know that I can hunt
for things is like typing issues or
typing errors basically yeah absolutely
and that I feel like that's a really
good transition into one of the tools
that you wrote I when was this like 2017
or something um this like this S3
decloaking tool or whatever this bucket
disclosure tool yeah do you want to like
talk about that a little bit cuz there's
you did a whole blog post and stuff but
I feel like yeah I've got you yeah the
blog post is is so what happened with
that blog post was like I I had fun bugs
that I wanted to explain but then I
realized okay I need to take one step
back like do people know what this is
and like do people know why this bug
happens and do people know what S3 is
and then like do people know what
internet is and like that that blog post
just grew up
no did I lose you yeah yeah I saw that
yeah so it it's looking right now it
says you're 1% uploaded do do you have I
see 1% uploading do do you have so
normally it goes from one to zero always
yeah so so do you have a a way to um
like make your internet stronger like
are you ethernet it in right now or are
you I can I can try I wonder what I have
for uh what I have on my phone instead
because it's it's weird because it
says oh wow
maybe could I've been the stupid person
in the
room what did you what did you do
I don't want to
say is he he's got proxy on right
now I turn it
off I now he's at 9% uploaded that was
definitely it all right so all right
goes to
S3 what mean it goes to
S3 wait wait uh I need to check my my oh
[__] yeah sorry it was my my mistake you
havex
yeah everything went through burp man
dude that's hilarious okay so so we
we've been dealing with some issues with
fr's cutting in and out for this past
like 20 minutes and you know what it was
he left freaking Bert proxy on so
classic hacker mistake here um so I'm
not sure really sure where where it cut
out but we'll we'll bring it back around
in peace burp States yeah see yeah dude
your burp file just blew up um but yeah
okay so you know you talked a little bit
about about you know the testing
methodology where you're you're thinking
about you know the code structures
you're thinking about things like
variable typing first and I will say you
know uh when you said typing for the
first time I was like yeah man you know
everybody types when they're hacking
like what the heck are you talking about
typing is one of our greatest talking
about typing as well oh my gosh that's
really funny but um so I guess I wanted
to dive a little bit into that so we've
seen the side already we've or at least
we' talked a little bit about the side
of like uh exploitation fronds you know
once you see a weird issue you you poke
at it you model out the code you know
you're thinking about how the developer
would have implemented it and you're
thinking about how you can validate
those assumptions by triggering
different edge cases throughout
throughout the code base
um I'm curious about flushing a little
bit more out about your your hack hacker
methodology because one of the things
we've seen in in the past with hackers
that have come on here is that you you
have a couple of extremes right you have
people that are you know um that go
really hard on the Recon stuff and
you've got people that that go really
hard on the um you know on the on the
manual hacking stuff right um and so uh
there there's definitely different types
of hackers but I've seen you do do both
and I think when you've got someone they
can do both it it it creates a crazy
result so but I did want to ask you you
know if you identify a little bit more
as as one or the other do do you
identify a little bit more as a manual
hacker or as a a wide hacker you know
focusing on recon to find weird stuff or
do you see yourself as a mix of the two
so I I began mostly so I think it's it's
a matter of difference in terms of like
where I'm at like so I would say I
started off of course manual because
everybody does that you need to figure
out what to do before you can automate
it sure went into like full fullon
automation like I wanted but but there
was always like I always had the
argument on like you can't automate if
you don't know what you're looking for
yeah and if your whole idea is to find
something you don't know of uh you can't
really automate it all so I was never I
was never a fullon
automation if that's the word yeah yeah
yeah I I was more on like uh I automated
a bunch of things I knew what I was
looking for but then I always kept this
thing where I'm like I'm going to save
it all and and I'm going to look through
it and I'm going to see The Oddities
myself because I don't know what what I
will find the things will happen much
faster than my knowledge about what it
what it is basically um but then then it
came I think it happened I took a break
from bug hunting or like break it was
probably like one and a half year or
something like probably during covid
mostly yeah where where I I didn't want
to do any live hacking events I wasn't
really looking for bugs in in any way
during almost two years I think um and
when I came back I kind of realized that
similar to I think what other bug
Hunters that like want to start off
realize is that there's so many people
that are doing automation that is like
ridiculous like seriously like they they
do things so fast I I tend to I spoke a
lot about my automation back in the day
and I told them like yeah I'm I'm doing
like every eight hours I'm looking and
they're like every eight hours I'm doing
it every 20 minutes every you know yeah
exactly and I'm like they're like you're
missing out on so many things I'm like I
can imagine yeah H and I'm like do I
want to invest the time to like speed up
my my automation just for those bugs and
I it came to the conclusion that like no
I don't I I rather I rather spend you
know manual time trying to figure out
really cool bugs than trying trying to
like like reach to the point where I'm
like at level with other automs yeah
automist I love that word it's awesome
word I think we're going to Art arts and
aut automist you know yeah I and it's
actually funny you know I actually had
that exact same path you know except I
sort of skipped the part where I was
doing manual hacking in the beginning
like when because there were so many
Resources by the time I started you know
when I started I guess in 2017 2018 you
know you had already put out talks you
know people were putting out talks on
how to do stuff so I had a pretty decent
flow of like bug Bounty writeups and
stuff like that to read and then I
leveraged into automation but then I
came to the same conclusion you did
which is like well maybe a little bit
different of one but essentially in in
order to compete at this at this game at
the top level you have to be constantly
refactoring your code yeah and it's a
grind right and it and it's going to
make it more of a pro you're going to be
become more of a programmer than you are
of a hacker because um you know you're
constantly having to refactor code um
and and so I I also sort of leveraged a
little bit more or switched over into
into manual hacking a little bit more
and it's been fun to see see the results
of that as well yeah um I I I think like
and when I also when I think about it
like when I mentally think about like
what do I
wanna like end up with or like what do I
want to succeed with it's not that I
like oh I I dream of finding a unclaimed
S3 bucket like that's that's really not
the the bug that I'm I'm like I will go
home exactly and be happy about the the
bug I will go home be happy about is the
one where I'm like I did this thing over
there and that gave me a little piece of
the puzzle and then I went over there
and did that and now I I can access the
server like with an RC like those are
the kind of bugs that I'm like oh I'm
gonna feel so proud and it it's like
it's gonna is gonna hold up for you know
more than a week probably sometimes a
year that bug has the value of like and
I I will not find that by writing
Automation and finding an unclaimed
bucket or a you know environment
variable file laying somewhere that
might be helpful into doing other things
but you know it's it the the fun the fun
things happen when when I go deep so I I
absolutely shifted over to like go deep
deep fullon you know go you know so deep
that that people are like but move on
man like stop looking at that thing H
but but I'm like keep digging and like
some sometimes there's something falling
out from it and like you realize you
know and I have I have all these
examples of you know running on a
private program but but still you know
grinding it for for months and and even
collaborating uh with with Matias in
this case and like we couldn't figure
figure one thing out and it was like how
does this work and why is it happening
and like he was he was at a concert I
think it was I don't know if it was like
Iron Maiden or something but he was at a
concert and I was writing him messages
because we often shat without the other
one responding like that's that's how we
communicate like as synchronous very
very much a synchronous and I was
writing to him like okay but this worked
like I don't know and and like it took
probably two or three hours and that
shut message history is like is a beauty
of itself because it's like this
happened I think it this oh oh my god oh
like it ended up in like being like
total disaster and and it was like you
know ring the bells and it like like one
of the most beautiful bugs I've ever
seen and it was just just that grind of
like we've been having this for for
months knowing that there's something
there but we couldn't figure it out and
it came to that conclusion it's like
it's so beautiful and it's and it's like
that's kind of bugs I want to like like
continue to you know bring home or you
know talk about in in the future yeah
absolutely I I I feel like for a long
time there was this like there was a lot
of manual hacking that went on and then
there was like a few years kind of like
right before Co like around Co and then
like during Co where like a lot of
people realize that there's so much
scope and there's so much stuff out
there that you can make a lot of money
just by doing Automation and like
automation isn't a particularly
difficult thing there's a lot of tools
out there stuff like nuclei and all
these like Frameworks and things that
exist that let you kind of just like
duct tape and bootstrap stuff together
and just like build these little
pipelines that do like a lot of like
really efficient work and so a lot of
people just really like Dove head first
into that and just started like scanning
for Stuff finding subdomain takeovers
finding bucket takeovers finding like
you know cves that you could just like
automate into you know easily
reproducible reports and bugs and like
that's a it's almost like a separate bug
Bounty space because it's like you're
basically at this point you're not
really like fighting over like
complexity of bugs or like how this app
like interacts with other parts of the
app or how this service or this website
might like you know be leveraged by
another part of the application or
another part of the company it's more
just like how fast is your tooling and
like how good can can you beat the other
person is your internet better is you
know are are is your scanning faster you
looking at the right things yes and I
agree love this manual hacking type of
mentality like me and Justin have
discussed this a little bit because as a
full-time Hunter I think it's a lot
easier to either fall more towards
automation or at least towards like less
complex findings because you need that
cash flow you need to be having reports
going in all the time but I also like I
love not feeling obligated to have
reports in because that gives you that
opportunity to do what you were talking
about like go deep with the application
get intimate as we like to
say learn the ins and outs of this
application become like almost a
developer essentially at the company
where you understand more about how
stuff is going on in the back end than
even somebody who works at the company
does because that really gives you all
those insights into where stuff is like
faltering or where there might be weird
mechanisms or these systemic patterns
like you talked about where you know you
realize oh this is like a common mistake
or Pitfall that they made maybe they
made this here and here and here and and
so on and I just love that that
mentality of just like you know ignore
the the sort of the The Flash and the
the Glamour and stuff just like bug
after bug after bug and find that really
really cool deep [__] and I I agree I
think I think one of the so I went full
bug hunting mode last I would say in
beginning of September October kind of
and and the decision I made was
happening during that summer and I
because I had those kind of you know
anxious uh things also like will I be
able to like pay my own Sal or like how
how how can I figure out the economics
around doing this fulltime uh and at
that point I I I had I had luck because
I I done like I did a few zoom on uh
like bugs on zoom and they paid me out
that summer and they paid really well
for those bugs so at that point I'm like
okay this is my buffer so I have a
buffer now of like if I would take like
my normal salary I would I would like
last this amount of months okay so these
months I can I can figure out if I
should you know go automation or
continue doing because those bugs I
found was like no automation it was just
like trying to figure out how everything
worked uh and I used that time to like
figure out first like where should I
hunt like what program takes care of me
what program you know treats my bug bugs
in a way that I feel appreciated or like
they value my my time and then also like
economical wise like where should I
spend my time to like align the return
on investment in a way that makes me not
stressed you know going forward um and
when I figured those things out like
where to look I still trying to figure
out like what programs I should focus on
but when I figured out some of it at
least that helped me a lot in into like
deciding that going deep was actually
you know uh monetary wise uh a good
decision for me to like don't be afraid
that that I won't be able to pay myself
a salary B yeah yeah I think you
definitely see if you look at the
numbers I think you'll see a higher um
return on investment of time right and a
highly a higher hourly rate if you do
deep bugs but the thing with with
automation is you get to have this and
and I experienced this when I was in
automation game if you take time off you
still get bugs right which is just huge
for like
Rel right you know like I don't know
what it is for me but like even if I
have a ton of money sitting in the bank
if I see that trending downward while
I'm taking a break or if I if I know
like hey I'm not finding bugs right now
that just bothers me you know and
imagine it's kind of like a it's it's
definitely a psychological problem um
you know for sure but because I think
you should be able to rest in both
States whether you just popped you know
100K in bugs and now you take you know a
couple weeks off and you've got that
100K sitting in the bank and you're like
all right I'm fine or whether you've got
you know 20K in the bank and you're you
see it going up and up and up and up
with the bugs you know those are the
same the same things uh but you know
psychologically it's it's it's very
different I think we also have a whole
episode about like picking the right
program and I think you you covered this
a little bit but it's really important
especially like when you're doing
full-time hacking to have the right
program you mentioned like once you find
like a program who really respects you
as a researcher and your reports and
like handles the things that submitting
and takes it very seriously and is you
know responsive and all these types of
things like it makes a really big
difference
to like I I I I almost want to say that
it increases the quality of the bugs
that you find later on because like you
have this relationship with the company
where you want to show them like hey I
found this really cool thing on on your
app like let me show you like let me
take it one step further like let me you
know I I bet you thought that last bug
was cool but how about this one and you
it's almost like a challenge and um if
you find a company that not only treats
you right but pays correctly like if you
have a a program say they pay like 5K
crits and their mediums are like
750 a couple Medi like you know you're
at like five mediums you're almost there
right and so it's like if you have
automation that's finding a bunch of
mediums versus it takes you a week or
two to find like a really bad crit but
it's only going to get paid 5K then that
tradeoff isn't always worth it but if
you have a program that's paying like
30k crits and maybe their mediums are
like one or 2 well that makes a big
difference and then your time is really
really worth like spending that time
finding that critical and not spending
it doing automation or like trying to
find a subd take yeah let let let me
jump in here and say you know I I think
we've made it clear enough but I want to
clarify we have tremendous respect for
people on both sides of the game um you
know and and you know uh the there's
definitely so many challenges of of
Recon and so many challenges of deep
diving stuff um so but hopefully this
has given a little bit of insight into
the the thought because I think All of
Us Joel more so than me but you know
have leveraged a little bit more into
the whole finding very high impact bugs
um you know with the majority of your
time and and and frons as well um and so
okay but we've already been talking for
a while and I two bullet points down on
my little list so let me let me let me
let me the start of the episode he's
like we got so much to cover like 30
minutes we've talked about two to yeah
I'm like super stressed over here cuz
Bam Bam Bam next next let me get back to
my list okay um no okay so I I do want
to ask a couple things and we'll keep
these pretty pretty rapid fire I think
um so you know you said you you identify
more now as as sort of a deep deep dive
hacker which I think is is on point um
and so and and I think I know the answer
to this because you already alluded to
it but I'm wondering how much time it
takes you to how much time you normally
spend on a program on average and how
much time it normally takes you to find
some bugs that you're proud of I would
say so I haven't jumped between programs
that much since I started with this
methodology but the one the times I've
done it during these two years I would
say I I think and this is like where
where the Imposter syndrome also hits
hard uh every time it's because whenever
you change your switch program you
basically have these you know sometimes
for me it can take up to like three days
until I actually find you know something
that I I think is relevant or or
valuable yeah and so so and i' I've
trained myself to not like I you know
you feel [__] during that time like you
hate yourself and you think you're a
fraud and you know all these kind of you
know thoughts come up H but at some
point you're like okay but no I I I know
this time is there you need to invest
the time and you know because and and
it's interesting also because if you
compare the first day you see see a
bunch of you know variable names or like
parameter names and like what the what
is this what is this I I have no idea I
just want to find a bug like ignore what
they are like and the third day you're
like oh I know exactly what that
parameter does and like what it does
okay so that's why so you need to like
spend those three days to like get that
you know mindset of like like the
taxonomy for example taxonomy is a huge
huge thing like what do they call you
know this kind of object and model like
as soon as so I I tend to like write
down tonomy for myself just to like
understand what is referencing what and
at at some point like that's also a
really good receipt for okay they're
calling it a little bit different here
like they use they used you know a
pascal case over here but there's snake
case over there and like those kind of
things is like indicators that there are
multiple people doing doing things here
and they've named it differently like
that's an indicator and
and those things takes probably like
three days to realize that this is an
outlier for example so let me let me
just highlight that just for the
listeners okay do you guys hear the
level uh of depth that he's he's
describing here he's describing the the
case the case of parameters and and and
he's he's taking notes on the the
verbage the the wording the taxonomy of
the various parameters and and end
points and and this is the kind of stuff
that you would think is getting too
minute too too detailed but is totally
not no no because every single every
single thing every time you go that deep
you get a further and further a little
bit little just a little little tiny bit
closer to understanding what it's what
it's looking like for this whole
application and and that that little
step little step by step there makes all
the difference in the world when it
comes to sort of box texting when at the
end of the day you're totally you know
you're totally looking at a black box
you know you have no idea what you're
working AB so there's some there's some
good tricks there I'm with you man like
I yeah I mean there's some good tricks
you can do like sometimes I just take
the full scope and I I search for the
host in burp search and then I copy
everything into an XML file and I have
like a unpack uh unpack burp state or
unpack burp uh list H and then I take
the body of the request and then I take
all the words I have and then I sort
them and make them unique and then I can
see like okay there's like intent id but
there's intent underscore ID and then
suddenly I can like go that way to like
find aties in in parameters as well yeah
and and those are those you know if you
got intent id Snak case and intentor ID
you know those are paramet that were
clearly implemented by different
developers right or or different you
know um life cycle flows right right
there right and so um you know there's
definitely a good chance that if every
single intent uppercase i ID is secure
that sometimes the intent underscore ID
will not be secure right so having that
that sort of Frameworks in place can
really help you um understand you know
that the app from a holistic perspective
and just take
take you know also I just want to shout
out that that ability to take notes to
to or not necessarily take notes but
like to process the data that you've got
there you know exporting to burp taking
the time to write the XML unpack script
which is something I've never done by
the way because it's just such a pain I
can share it's awesome yeah that that
would be great um is something that will
differentiate you from other hackers
right you don't even have to know that
it's the right thing to do you know so
many people are like man should I spend
my time doing this doesn't matter it's
going to make you unique as a hacker
let's say you do that nothing comes of
it you still saw more of the application
than someone else who who hasn't done
that right you you looked at those
parameters a little bit differently you
know because you unpacked everything so
yeah it's the things that make us unique
hackers like that that that really allow
different people to find different crazy
bugs yeah I also think that there's like
a whole aspect like the whole becoming
almost like a developer within that
environment where if you learn the ter
techology and you learn what things mean
so many developers use abbreviations and
stuff to like represent things like they
they might uh you know take something
that represents some system right and
they might abbreviate it as three
characters and just start using that as
an acronym like throughout their
application throughout different like
you know endpoints or parameter calls
and stuff A lot of times I'll look at
something like that and I'll say like
what like what is what is this like what
is this these three letters what is this
supposed to mean like what what does
this represent to the developer and once
you identify at a lower level like what
does this actually mean what are they
referencing when they're saying you know
these three characters or whatever you
can really start to unpack hidden
functionality and this type of stuff
that may even exist that you know you'll
start to stretch to different ideas like
oh maybe if they're calling uh an
endpoint with a different three-letter
acronym maybe I can toss my three-letter
acronym that I know what this means
maybe I can hit a different service or
something right and I and I think like
getting to that level of just being like
what does that mean or what is this
parameter doing what do this represent
you get that much deeper be able to
deeper within the application much
easier yeah yeah 100% um so let me let
me ask this then um I I have
seen I'm thinking specifically at the
last live hacking event we were both at
when we were sitting at this table and
we were like slamming our heads into a
wall um on this one specific bug for a
while um how how often do you find
yourself sitting in front of a request
and trying things sort of incessantly
versus sitting back staring at the
ceiling and thinking about the bug like
and I and I know that this is kind of a
hard question because it's very um you
know abstract but just give me your gut
your gut feelings on how much time you
spend actually Hands-On iterating versus
uh just sort of thinking and ideating
yeah so so I have I have a bunch of
things I I tend to do when I I get to
the point where I I can't figure it out
yeah like it's all everything from you
know collecting my own kind of word list
from that uh asset just to like find you
know things in there that like can make
me understand what this is uh up to up
to the point where where as you said
like I I take a walk and I'm like
thinking about it and like how why does
it behave like it does or what is it
trying to you know what data is it
trying to fetch or or similar so
sometimes I I would say both work
sometimes you know complete brute
together with very context related
information yeah like for example
generic word lists for me is not really
helping that much I wouldn't say that
you know word list found on you know a
really large word word list works that
well I would the ones that work are are
when when you can like apply the context
to what you're actually looking at
that's when you're getting the nice nice
hits and and but but in in in in the
other aspect also is like sometimes you
just need to think about it and you know
Google error messages is like an awesome
thing as well as soon as you see an
error message that is like this is not a
generic error message like then you can
start digging down like maybe it's this
and maybe this is the database I'm
injecting into or whatever or even maybe
an error message that kind of looks like
a generic error message but is worded
specific yes or it has like you know a
format that is that is very very
different from also like if error
messages look the same on a Target and
suddenly one error message doesn't that
that is also like okay the all the other
ones had you know square brackets around
the error code but this one does not
like those could be also indicators that
okay there's another thing causing this
error message yeah no absolutely
absolutely I think like one of the
really underutilized things is Googling
stuff with quotes around it AB all the
time just like if I see an error you
Google something with quotes around it
it does exact yeah yeah exactly like
that we did that at the last event you
know the thing that we're talking about
right now like what is this like what is
this system what is this using what is
this technology and just search the
error message and immediately there's
100 Google results all mentioning the
same exact thing you're like oh okay
it's that okay that's that's it so last
question about the hacker methodology
piece so it seems like you spend a good
amount of time on your targets it give
me just sort of like a gut feeling on
like how how much time you spend on the
average
Target I would say so I would say three
days is is an investment first you might
not get anything from it so I've done
this like short assessments kind of
thing where I'm like okay I'm GNA focus
on this program and what what has
happened for me is like one and a half
week yeah is is is a is a for me where I
know I'm going to find something good I
don't know how bad it will be but I know
I will find something that will be good
so one and a half week has been a really
good uh way for me but also like you
have kids so it's like right you don't
know where where you going to spend that
one and a half week are you going to
spend it on the night are you going to
spend it you know in the office times or
are you going to spend it like at all
like there could be you know and and
often like when you sub you know a bunch
of bugs at the same time or like in the
in the matter of of days uh you always
have this trios you know massage yeah
that is like it it can be especially
like my my reports are like sometimes
two to 4,000 words uh my my reports are
insane man like they are they are my
blog posts are sometimes are small
compared to my blog post oh my gosh I'm
writing them manually it's not like copy
pasting a boil plate of like how it's
actually like step by step showing you
know sometimes I I'm showing even how I
came to the conclusion that there
there's a bug and I have like a very
long impact explanation and you know
everything is like typed from from from
the frontal cortext yeah 100% yeah but
so but then you have so that half week
afterwards is like three three AR
basically yeah there's always that like
getting through yeah you get it through
they find out it's not a dupe and then
it's another week of yes this is how you
reproduce
it that's a good that's a good side
effect also of going like deep into a
program like compare like live hacking
events are are an exception to the to
the rule but but I haven't duped once in
in all all like this full time since
August last year uh except for live
hacking you DED me you
stupid like I was like that to so so
like let's say for example that program
right that was a that was a challenge um
and and so how long would you spend on
something like that that one I spent I
to be honest that one was new for me so
I didn't know what to expect so I
submitted that bug only uh and it was
two hours or something yeah I mean I
didn't spend [__] on on that fre funny
thing was that it was I think it was
very valuable for me not to spend more
time because I had a hunch that they
might not be as you know receptive to
that vulnerability receptive to the
report as I thought so in in that sense
I think I did a good investment not to
spend more time yeah and that's also a
thing where you like especially when it
comes to new programs I'm like very very
restrictive on like like the worst thing
you can do is like you spend much time
you find a really bad bug and then you
continue and you submit bugs and you
have no response yet and you're like
investing so much time and then suddenly
they respond and they don't treat you in
a good way yeah and you're like why did
I continue yeah you spoke really wi I
heard that before from from other people
in the in the in the podcast also it's
like do don't invest too much in the
beginning like you won't you won't gain
anything from submitting you know 50
bugs in the begin you're you're only
gambling with your own time like don't
do that absolutely abely you can gamble
with that time when you know the
receiver and you know what what to
expect from them have to validate
validate the program and validate your
threat model because on on one hand you
know you could be it could be the
program just being [__] right that's one
possibility you know they could just be
a bad program or you have misaligned
your ex exactly you think is a is a
threat or not or you could have
misaligned your threat model and and and
that's not anybody's fault except maybe
you know one could argue that the team
should have uh you know provided more
insight into their threat model sure in
their policy which I would love to see
more of in general but you know like you
said it's a gamble if you're not if
you're not you know validating that
threat model in advance because um you
know it's very easy for issues to to to
come out of that um sure and so okay all
right first section of my of my of my
notes are are done here um so here's
what here's where I'm thinking we're
going to go from here
okay I have uh compiled together let's
see 1 2 3 four five
six uh articles some of the best hacking
articles I've ever read written by
France over the years starting in 2017
spanning all the way up to I think 2022
or 2023 the latest one um and I just
want to kind of walk through these and
talk about mentality I want to talk
about technical details of them so I
hope you reviewed them because I don't
know about you but I if I if I wrote
something you know 6 months ago and then
somebody asked me about it you know six
months later then I'm screwed uh because
I don't remember anything but we'll see
um okay so the first one and we'll link
all these in the description as well I
would it's not even something that I
would recommend it is mandatory reading
for any listener of critical thinking to
go and read all of these um so please
keep that in mind um the first one that
I wanted to talk about was this whole uh
AWS S3 thing so yeah um if any you know
for the listeners here
um S3 bucket takeovers and S3 bucket
issues now are one it's one of the most
hottest it's one of the hottest topics
in in Cloud security um and all of this
originates with this man right here fron
um who who sort of coined the S3 yeah
the S3 bucket takeover um and so I I
want to kind of you know flash back to
2017 here um you're seeing this new
technology sort of coming on the scene
and you're seeing it implemented in lots
of different places on all these
different programs how do you come how
do you identify this
issue so it was actually earlier earlier
it was actually 2014 the first the first
blog post about it was in 2014 October I
think yeah um and and back then back
then it was basically you know every
time you saw a 404 you like just like
moved on yeah exactly because it's like
wasn't nothing is there right uh so I I
think we we came to the conclusion like
I think it
was both S3 and there was some something
else that was also like I think heru was
and GitHub GitHub Pages was one of those
so I think we just came to the
realization because we were looking at
like detectify was was getting built at
the same time and a lot a lot of things
we were doing was around you know
Finding subdomains and and trying to
identify what what they were running and
at some point I think we we figured out
that like okay so uh we started signing
up on these these uh you know I think
was Shopify as well like this these
Sauce Services and suddenly realized
that you could just like there were no
verification at all like we were under
the like assumption in the beginning
that you need to validate your your you
own the domain because that's how you do
you know everything else when it comes
to like Gmail or you know when you want
to run Gmail for example and and and and
realize that okay nobody's actually
doing this because it's like a
convenience thing to to like not use
that validation part uh and we started
reaching out to all these companies and
writing like okay somebody can just
hijack all these these uh companies uh
because they're pointing to you and some
of these some of the Prov ERS were just
like yeah but they're not our customer
anymore so why reading between the lines
that was what they were saying like it's
not our fault that you know they're not
paying us anymore or you know you mean
somebody's gonna have to pay us to hack
them I like that someone that's not our
customer yeah go for it no but so so I
think and and and a lot of them were
like we already know about this this is
no no big deal and and we were we were
screaming loud like please do something
something about it like add the
validation do you know whatever like
something you need to do something and
And when everybody responded like not a
single company responded with like yeah
you're right oh my gosh we we realized
like I we need to get it get it out
there and then it was just a matter of
like how many more are there I I think
the first blog post we had we had like
14 maybe providers like big providers
that we decided to to announce uh but at
the same time there were you know a huge
amount popping up since then of course
still popping up to this day and uh and
S3 is one of those that that like keeps
on lingering uh I know that there are
there are some changes happening or the
like you can't change S3 but you can you
can do implementations above it that is
like safe so there's something called S3
access points which is their addition to
it and access points always get like a
unique um hash in the in it so you can't
CL reclaim an access point so that's
that's like AWS solution to the problem
is to like make access point the the way
to actually access a bucket um but yeah
I think and like one of the big
challenges in the beginning also when it
come to S3 was to figure out what the
bucket name was H it wasn't always clear
even though you have it in the eror
message it wasn't always clear uh what
the bucket and especially sometimes you
do want to know the bucket name even if
it's exists and I think that was the the
the whole idea with the bucket disclosed
was to figure out what the bucket was
named because if you knew what the
bucket was named you can make additional
API calls on the side uh to that bucket
to see access level errors and stuff
yeah that's that's such an amazing
little little script there um and we'll
we'll L it down below yeah we'll link it
down below and it does still work to
allow you to identify what the name of a
is and there's lots of really cool error
based stuff you can do with that too
where you're like creating um invalid
signed URLs that fail in such a specific
way that it like leaks the bucket name
so cool we have the same one me and
Matias built the same one in the
beginning of this year for uh Google
Cloud Storage ni so we have a we have
seven seven decloaking methods for for
uh for cloud storage uh and it's kind of
helpful in cloud storage as well because
some times you really want to know the
name yeah and it's very important for
depending on how your setup looks like
so I think I will talk with Matias to
get it out as well I think it's very fun
to have that's awesome decloaking I I
love the the that like terminology
because I think this applies to more
than just S3 buckets where like this is
it's very similar to like origin server
detection where you know if you're
trying to bypass a W for example you
find what the origin server is or a way
to talk to the origin server directly
and mimic as if your requests are are
going through the ra WFT then often
times you can just bypass the wa
directly and it's very similar to like
S3 where you might have some subdomain
that's maybe it's talking to a backend
service instead of actually just being a
c name um to the bucket directly and if
you can figure out someone to error it
or you know get get it to basically
Oracle to what the bucket is then you
can you know maybe read some data that
you shouldn't have access to you can
list the bucket maybe you can do you
know whatever it really depends on the
context I love that that methodology
yeah the decloaking is is applicable in
so many aspects like you mentioned as
well like with a reverse proxy or an
origin structure you know if you can
leak that backend URL there's there's a
decent chance that you might be able to
use that in a vhost you know somewhere
else at a load balancer level and hit
that backend server directly and just
bypass all of the middleware
authentication that they've got in place
so we've seen that time and time again
and it's a it's an awesome technique and
and that's another one of the things
that kind of comes out of the security
research is is the the impact the the
conceptual impact is very wide reaching
it's
different um there LS of can into with
this with this blog post that will link
the and actually I didn't even have the
one I'm looking back now because you
said there's one in 2014 and then
there's also another one which I missed
in 2016 where you're talking about
cloudfront stuff and um oh yeah and oh
that was fun yeah that was good memories
and the the the uh the trailing dot dude
like oh yeah there was a bug there was a
bug like in a live hacking event right
yeah just like two years ago or
something that that one of the bugs the
best bugs in that live hacking event was
a trailing dot yeah so it still happens
so for those of you excuse me for those
of you that don't know about that
actually you know France why don't you
tell them a little bit about trailing
Dot and what that does conceptually yeah
so I think the the blog post mentions
specifically cloudfront so what happened
with cloudfront was that when you went
to in this case it was like paypal.com
it wasn't paypal.com I think it was
car.com so you went to car.com and you
would be served a page through
cloudflare uh but the whole idea with
like how internet works or like the
dubdub dub Works was that H you can
always add Cloud Player or Cloud front
Cloud front Cloud front okay yes Cloud
front yeah you can always add like a
trailing dot to a domain yeah because
that's the it's called like fqdn like a
fully qualified domain name is actually
ending with a DOT they've just removed
it for like I think for like Simplicity
or something yeah so a trailing dot
should always you know serve similar
things or just give an error or whatever
and in cloudfront it gave an error but
it gave the error that looked like
nobody has claimed that domain so I went
into cloudfront now you can't do this
anymore because cloudfront wants you to
validate that you own the domain but
back then you could just add it as a c
name to your Cloud front and it had like
a client side validation so you couldn't
add a trailing dot it would say you
can't but if you like capture the proxy
if you take the like it was like a G
grpc request and you modified that
little thing in the request with a DOT
you would add that to your to your own
host and then you could serve whatever
you want on the on the trailing Dot and
funny thing was that cloudfront has
cookie logging so it will log your
cookies also and and cookies are working
both on the fq fqdn and the regular
domain so if you had cookies sign into
PayPal and or car.com and then went to
car.com dot you would I would get your
cookies um and I started getting those
logs and I saw like people were clicking
on emails and then I realized why are
they getting this from clicking on
emails because they write please hello
my dear friend go to car.com Dot and
then the dot would be you know included
in the link because I mean it's a link
right uh so that was the reason why so
many to the dot domain because it was
like in the end of a sentence wow so
this doesn't even really require user
interaction at that point because people
are just going to that domain natively
yeah yeah yeah absolutely so that was
that was the scary part H and and it was
a long process from that part like
PayPal obviously fixed it by by
reclaiming it themselves yeah but then
it was a long discussion with AWS also
getting them to like you know you need
to normalize this and so they also
treated this as a as a bug themselves
wow do you feel like a lot of the bugs
that you found have led to those
sweeping sort of advs changes like uh
yes yes yes I do like one of one of the
one of the things that I I talked a lot
on I had a OAS event uh talking about
the DNS and Route
53 uh and and suddenly they took a took
a couple of years but they fixed it and
that is one of the most impressive p
I've ever seen like I have no I like I
dream of the day somebody tells me how
that mitigation was done like seriously
like it's impressive as hell like they'
do they they do something out of the out
of the box thinking there be honest they
really do and I've tried me and chubs
and plenty of other hackers have spent
so much time trying to bypass that
mitigation because if you can there's a
treasure Trove of bugs
uh there you know being able to reclaim
these these domains um but yeah that
dude that was a sad day for me man
whenever they fixed that that bug
because that was my that was my cash cow
when I was in in uh in you know
automation also have these you know oh
[__] now now the curve going down right
it happens in automation as well
especially it I think it punches you
harder when those things happen in
automation I I I forgot to say that but
but when automation gets with something
happen with your Automation and goes
like that that's a panic you don't want
to end up with like that Panic is worse
worse than having a vacation and you go
you see it go down absolutely 100%
especially when you've dumped so much
time into a technique like I spent weeks
you know months of actual time you know
like on hands on the keyboard time
refining my my Route 53 flow and and and
just to be clear Route 53 takeovers are
still possible in some capacity but um
it's it's very limited
compared yeah yeah and so um definitely
changed a lot and and that was that was
The Day The Day the Music Died For Me
That was the that was the day that that
I was like you know what I think I'm
done with this [__] um and so yeah all
right so man I missed so many articles
you know when I when I just going back I
just kind of cherry-picked some of my my
fr's you know favorite moments but now
I'm starting why I post post things
because the bugs turn boring after a
while right so this is this is my let to
like eliminate me from looking at them
anymore because I hope that someone else
will look for them that sounds pretty
notes but it's it's my yeah that's true
but it's my way of like moving forward
like if I if I out like myself in a way
that like like my secret tricks if I
just get them out there I can move on in
finding new new things yeah it pushes me
forward and that's amazing for the
community too what a benefit and and
friends can I ask I mean do you do you
like writing in particular like do would
you say that you enjoy writing yeah I
think I think it's a necessity almost
since I spend so much time on like
writing reports yeah however like it's
hard for me to like sit down and say now
I'm going to skip hacking and now I'm
going to write a a you know a blog post
about something
because as what often happens is like
I'm not writing a short little blog post
of what I did yesterday it's like it's
going to be like a huge artic
and I need like I have one here that
that I'm I'm still cooking on it's been
cooking since January and I know for
fact that I like I can't start you know
directly going at it I need I need to
explain a lot of [__] before I can come
to the to the conclusion of what I found
and it's going to take it's going to
take a week two weeks maybe and it's
going to be painful like a a lot a big
part of writing blog post for me is like
painful painful you know going back back
and realize how hard everything was or
how long it took and like I really want
to emphasize that also in the latest
blog post I have it's like it's a big
focus on how much pain goes into like wa
like spending that time and it's great
that you mention that because I will and
and I'm not sure if you're talking
because you mentioned just a second ago
you you you had a a vlog post you're
working on I think yesterday so I'm very
interested to pick your brain on that
but um I'm I'm talking I'm talking about
um the account hijacking using Dirty
Dancing one one of my notes for that one
and it's on the list that we'll talk
about later but that that blog post is
so beautiful because it talks about the
ups and downs of doing security research
right and it talks about like this whole
concept of well you know these gadgets
you know needed to leak these tokens and
stuff like that the stars have to align
in so many ways for these to be there
and absolutely and when you go out there
and you're like man I feel like this
might be a systemic issue you're
challenging something and you're and
you're you're betting against the odds
there and you're really like putting
yourself out there by spending a [__]
ton of time to assess so many different
different things and I think it was
great that you represented it that way
in the in the article and I I think not
to not to destroy the discussion later
about it but one big thing with that the
the whole the whole idea about like my
whole theory was not based on finding
that bug yeah like I had zero bugs such
for such a long time during I didn't
even have one you know I I I had zero
bugs I just had a theory that oh this
would be so beautiful if if you could
get this working like I had a discussion
in the office here I came here and like
yeah I'm I'm having a like a theory I'm
working on but I don't know if it's
going to work like this is my idea and
if this works then maybe like crazy
right and then and I'm like I had
nothing so so that was it was such a
gamble it was it was 100% a gamble on
like let's then go look for it like how
like I had no idea how to do it so that
was very painful also in the in the way
of like oh I'm really trying to as you
said like getting the Stars to align but
then suddenly like one of the my my
favorite programs turned out to have
that thing that that was the like the
trigger that okay there I I'm right like
there is something here can I come up
with other you know idea gadgets or
whatever so everything came out of ideas
not from uh like real life that was the
big difference with that blog post all
other blog posts are based on reality
first and then I'm moving backwards
trying to like see a systemic issue
about it this was 100% idea trying to
squeeze it in it like very fitted into
10 years since the blog post I learned
from like everything was aligned like
can I can I write a good oos blog post
10 years after my idol
wrote one that would be that would be so
it it was very much like I really need
to find a way for this to work so yeah
so when you're like approaching stuff
like we we've talked a little bit about
this of sort of like the really out of
thebox type of thinking versus the like
more like data driven context driven
developer driven type of methodology do
you do you like going down that route of
more just like maybe this is happening
or do you find that it doesn't really
pay off most of the time so so it it
doesn't pay off a lot of the times uh so
I I mentioned the Google Cloud Storage
the cloak like that was the whole idea
with that research was to find systemic
issues around that like we found some of
them but they weren't you know I
wouldn't say you couldn't execute them
in bug Bounty programs uh you could
maybe execute them you know if you want
to report things to Google but but for
GOOG in Google's aspect they wouldn't be
like really bad bugs they would be like
coincidental
misconfigured together with like odd you
know conf like odd configurations for
Google but also for the customer using
them and stuff but so that turned out to
be like we don't really have anything we
have a a decloak tool maybe that could
be fun to blog about maybe we can do
like a decloak blog post talking about
the the ways we found these decloaking
mechanisms and and maybe that could be
interesting like now I'm like now I'm
forcing myself to write these blog posts
because it would be weird talking about
the blog post that I hav written so do
you I mean you mentioned before one
motivation for writing the blog post is
you know it gets it out of your head and
allows you to move on to something
different so I think that's a really
great takeaway um I wanted to ask about
because you're releasing all of these on
detectify um you know on the detectify
blog um and and so is that an
intentional decision is that to help you
know detectify build brand because let
me just provide some context from from
my perspective as a hacker like you know
I I don't use detectify I'm not I'm not
an organization you know where where I
could use detectify but my respect for
detectify is like you know very high
because of all this super high quality
research same sort of thing you see with
asdo right where they're constantly
putting out high quality research um so
you know besides the motivation of of um
you know getting it out of your head
what are some other motivations that you
have for doing the blog post and hosting
them on detectify I think I think one
important aspect is like they I've been
a part of it for so long so it's
important for me to
like H I resp like I respect the whole
team so much that I want to show them
that that it's like very important part
of who I am and where I'm at as well as
like sometimes I actually like me and
Frederick sometimes collaborate on blog
posts and he's he's you know uh working
here uh from day to day as well so I
think it's like this office for me is a
very good way of uh doing you know uh
what's it called like brainstorming and
things like trying to figure out things
so of most often uh I I tend to present
to them first what I'm thinking about
sure and then because of the knowledge
here I can get like feedback on like
maybe you should do this maybe you
should do that or maybe you should call
it dirty dancing which was
like Emily in the office like you should
call it it's like sounds like dirty
dancing to me like yeah that's a good
name so I I think that it's very helpful
having a context nearby where where a
lot of people know exactly what you're
talking about and and you know the the
technology so I think that's that's very
helpful also like I'm I'm obviously
still a part of the tech by right not
not that I'm writing any code and I
shouldn't but but but it's it's and I
think also like I I don't have a big
gain I think on like making my own
personal blog and creating a name out of
that I'm more than happy to like attach
myself to a company that I that I value
and and like am a part of much more than
than doing it you know privately trying
to build a brand and and you kind of get
a two for one when you do it because I
mean I don't know maybe maybe it's just
the fact that your brand is already
established you know in the in the
community right um
but uh you know when we look at this
blog post and we say Okay detective is
releasing this but fron is writing it
you know you kind of get um you know
it's almost like to to put it in SEO
terms it's almost like you get domain
Authority on on detectify and you get
you know Community Authority from pron
so it's a good it's a good it's a good
thing and man what I'm thinking about
where to go next here there's so many
you know we could go down the route of
like let's talk about about Dirty
Dancing we could talk about about uh you
know H hacking plus entrepreneurship and
I think that that is where I want to go
with this next one which is like
so you you go you come into this company
you know you started detectify with you
know years ago with with you know Matias
and and them all based off of you know
uh that security research what what role
do you play in this company and like
what cuz to me it kind of seems like you
just kind of run around and you're like
hey guys what if we did this blog post
and like what if like have you seen this
cool technical idea and like who the
heck are you to this company like so
it's a good that you say that because
like one of the things happening with
the companies that I I've built when
they are growing up there is like a big
discussion on like how do we squeeze
France into the regular you know
day-to-day basis like what can we do so
I was I was a a scrum what was that
called I was uh like a scrum breaker no
scrum Breer scrum breaker okay so I went
in and like we should do this and like
the whole scrum team is like we hate you
I hate so I was I was the scrum breaker
and and and so and every time when when
it gets like more than 40 50 people it's
like how do we fit this weird person
individual into this organization and
it's like yeah how did you how did you
so one of the things that I find really
difficult and even just the small
entrepreneurial that Endeavors that I've
been a part of is delegating like and so
when You' started these companies have
you had other players that are you know
the executive players from the very
beginning or how do you how was it hard
for you to give up control or delegate
um you know uh jobs to different people
and how did you move out of that okay so
I I could say like this one of the
benefits I had was to have a business
partner early on that was very much into
sales and also into managing that's
awesome uh I think that was the helpful
part so I always had to you know take
the technical jacket on and and and be
the one in both in charge of the team
doing the technical things but also ER
together with the team trying to figure
out how to solve certain things like in
the beginning it was me building you
know building uh everything and then we
we got like our first employee that was
the developer and we we we worked really
well together so we could start building
it also like this was an e-commerce
platform it's still alive it's called
Sentra it was smaller then it's bigger
now uh but but so when we started
building Sentra uh we uh I was always
down on the floor so to say I was always
a part of the team that was like my
whole concept of like I my my way of
managing in the technical team was to be
just one one of the guys like I was
never you know doing any salary talks
that was never my my um my job job I was
not doing any one in ones so one and
once was do done by someone else I was
the you know CTO in the way that like
I'm gonna play with new technologies I'm
gonna try to execute them if I find
something and I'm gonna I'm gonna
together with the team like sometimes
make a smaller team out of the bigger
team just to make something reality as
fast as possible but that thing only
works when you go up to like when we we
turn into 50 or 60 people that's when it
it's like really hard to like take some
people out of the dev team and get to do
some fun new thing and then trying to
move them put them back again and like
everybody's happy like that that's not
how it works so it it became really hard
for me to like squee like be squeezed in
and like get to play with the fun toys
uh so I I've come to the realization
that like I can I can build I'm I'm
really good at like starting from zero
yeah and then when when we we get up to
40 50 people I'm
like yeah just roll it out of the
picture yeah exactly that's that's
basically yeah and I think it's good for
everyone if I do that because else it's
just so much politics around I love how
he says that else else is this you like
else literally the prr exception on is
making into the verbage that's that's
amazing um yeah yeah that think that's
that's the the the aspect of it is is
yeah I don't know if that was an answer
to the question it is man it's it's a
great I mean what a great position to be
in what a dream of a position and I
think so many people that have the
entrepreneurial itch that are also
technical people dream of positions like
that of like okay I'm I'm seite you know
I I have influence on this organization
but all the crappy stuff like sales and
management I'm going to just not do that
and I'm going to do I'm GNA
we all know that this is how it works
best too when you're operating in your
area of expertise when you're operating
in your passion so that just highlights
the the importance of trying to find
someone who who you know that's a
partner that's very passionate about
sales and and management and that sort
of thing so that you each can operate in
your own sort of you know expertise
genre yeah exactly yeah expertise I also
love that like co-founder model where
like it's really hard to be good at
everything and I think it's much more of
an anomaly to be good at like both
aspects of the business like both the
technical and like the the the really
refined like fine point like how does
the product or feature service or
whatever actually work versus like
getting it sold and like getting
customers and getting it marketed and
that kind of stuff and trying to balance
both of those things as one person is
really really difficult um and
oftentimes you either have to subsidize
that temporarily by like either taking
debt or using your own personal money to
like pay people to do that or you get
just like drowned in doing everything by
yourself and every single day is like a
12 to 16 hour day of just like doing
sales and also writing the product and
also sending emails and yeah doing like
everything at once and so if you can
start out by having that balance it's
just like really it's not that I it's
not that we realized that to begin with
like I had salary talks but the only
thing happening was that I raised
everybody's salary like way too much so
it's like we we came like we we had a
gift talks for FR no and I had we had
like a Christmas gift thing and we were
like giving away iPhones and it's like
we had so little money on on the first
day of the year afterwards and it was
like maybe I shouldn't do this uh I
should not be the one in charge of like
because I wanted everybody happy like
that was my because yeah so I I came
into this podcast thinking fron is like
some hacker entrepreneurial genius and
now I'm leaving thinking FRS is running
around annoying people until he doesn't
have to do the parts of the job that he
doesn't want him to
probably that's the truth I guess but
it's like yeah I mean there's some truth
also to like uh we we kind of realized
like where where do where is my
execution the best like the best place
to be in and like that that was the that
was the way to like grow very fast I I
make a joke about that but but really
you know it it that's the wisest thing
to do truly and and and so so um yeah
there's there's I guess one of this is
more of a personal question for from
from my perspective one of the things
I've struggled with is is you know
releasing that and and being like all
right you know I actually just need to
delegate this job to someone else yeah
and and the reason why I struggle with
that is because it's like okay well a
lot of times in the beginning that means
giving up Equity right and and because
you don't have the money or if you do
have the money you don't want to you
know I don't know just SN all of your
life savings into a thing which actually
he about entrepreneurs doing all the
time which is just you know awesome and
inspiring um I mean is that is that what
you what you had to do I mean is that
what is that what you need to do is you
just need to give give the equity so
that you don't have to do this part of
the job and that's the right decision
from your perspective I I wouldn't say
we had to do that from the
GetGo at all uh to begin with but we
came I think uh our our perspective of
it has changed
because of experience like in the
beginning we could actually you know
with a salary get people engaged and get
people to actually do things and build
and have fun like we had a lot of fun
building these companies because it was
so much Hands-On we were like out there
we were you know I was developing things
next to the customers you know at like
there was a big like spectacle around
you know how we how we did business in
the beginning uh but but then I think um
oh I lost the thread uh yeah what was
the question
well the question is is like I guess at
the end of the day what I need you to
tell me is
that to give to to delegate these jobs
right so so what happened what happened
then was that I uh when it comes to
H oh I had it yeah it came and then I
lost it and it's funny I I I get those
same sort of things when when I'm in
these situations on a podcast in
particular cuz it's so hard to keep much
to explain there but it's I lost it I I
think I think it's so yeah so what
happened was that we got people employed
without like giving away actual Equity
because we both had a really fun place
to be at because of the spectacle but
also because they like we were paying a
fair kind of salary yeah but then we
like during all these years and I think
also it's like a um like how the society
works like there's a much more talk now
about you know getting Equity when
you're building a start up and stuff and
we we never we never really called
oursel a startup because we we made
money from day one so we we never you
know had a problem with the you know uh
MoneyWise uh but I think that's an
important uh you know that that's an
important factor there because if you're
making money from day one if you build
your MVP and you actually have that
validated by by receiving money then all
of these issues of like start start to
disappear because at the end of the day
you can just hire someone and pay them
you know exactly because you you you do
have the money but then I mean a lot of
a lot of the money I made in bug
bounties have been invested into these
companies so we all we had that all we
didn't have that from the beginning
because that that wasn't how how it
worked in the beginning but but during
during all these years we had that as a
kind of a way to solve a bunch of
problems with money obviously but but
but then we also realized that a lot of
people that that stayed for a really
long time it was much more valuable for
them and for us to give them equity and
a part of the company yeah so that that
that happened after a longer while but
now it's like almost you know a standard
thing like if you join a startup you're
getting a a part of the equity in some
form of you know um like a pool similar
uh Equity pool and uh but but back then
it wasn't and I think that was helpful
also into like you know coming getting
into that but but I would say like what
what happened now later on with you know
getting a a CEO for example like we we
didn't want to be the CEO of this
company so we we you know found or the
CEO found us in those cases it's always
you know you need to give up Equity
obviously um because you you want them
to be like you know they have to be
fully on you know active on on getting
the company to to where everybody else
wants wants it but uh so I would say it
depends on what kind of position you
want to fill or what kind of things like
you don't need to give away equity for
for every every single you know person
that joins unless you like you can find
some good Z money yeah yeah that's true
but I mean you can find some some nice
Equity pooling kind of things where you
get like a you know a vesting time and
stuff so you know that people will stay
at least that time like but but it all
matters if if you have like very key
positions like then then it that
discussion is relevant so so I I wanted
to ask one more thing and and I think
you know critical thinking as a podcast
focused specifically on bug bounty
hunting so the entrepreneurial piece of
this while is absolutely fascinating to
me and I think many of our listeners
share that interest um I think I may
move a lot more of my entrepreneurial
questions into a different segment that
maybe we'll release under the premium
Discord Channel or something like that
um but uh one last thing that I wanted
to ask about this was when you were
taking bug Bounty money and and putting
it into the companies how were you
thinking about that mentally were you
thinking about that as this is France's
money that he's investing into the
company or were you thinking I'm working
for the company and I'm I'm generating
this income that is just getting direct
directly put right into the company yeah
so what what happened was we me and my
business partner we're 50-50 and uh this
was my way of
uh providing so what I did was providing
quick capital and like monetary wise the
capital but he was building like he he's
he was in charge of being the CEO and
and everything in the beginning so so he
was in charge of building the company
you know making the company more
valuable but I was bringing in the the
quick Bock to actually make it you know
much more uh easy to solve problems and
to scale easier yeah yeah to scale
easier so so we we both agree that like
we're putting in different things but we
need to align somewhere here where like
it's fine for me and still fine for him
and like I think it's a weird balance
also especially when when the bug bount
is like you can go from one month you're
getting you know this amount and and a
live hacking event you get this amount
and and it it turned really complex in
the end and it turn turns into a lot of
money if you're if you're good at what
you're doing so
uh I think it in the end it it was
probably like we we don't have that this
this uh setup anymore uh and I I think
that's that's probably for the best
because it can clearly like misalign you
know interests over time especially when
when it when it when it you know now
we've got a bug Bounty company where
fron does hacking and then we pay
employees you know like yeah yeah is
fr's bugs yeah exctly great like bug
hunting as a I don't know what to call
it it's like funding by bug bounty
hunting yeah for sure um okay so we'll
we'll I'm gonna I'm going to go ahead
and and cross off my hacking plus
entrepreneurial section here um thank
you for those awesome in insights frons
that's that's awesome and and I I know
you and I have had some personal chats
you know from time to time about uh
entrepreneurialship
entrepreneurship plus um that's a good
one was
entrepreneurial ship um no uh you know
plus hacking so uh definitely a lot of
wisdom to be received there um bringing
us back on track to the to the hacking
stuff I did want to talk about one of my
favorite um talks that you've ever done
which just essentially looked like
prophecy to me looking back in in the
past which is you're attacking modern
web Technologies talk that you did in
2018 um uh almost exactly 5 years ago
yeah um and attacking modern web
Technologies there was so many awesome
pieces to this there was um app caches
and service workers uh you know there
was post message stuff there was upload
policies yeah the the policies the S3
policies all sorts of stuff all over the
place so um once again mandatory
mandatory reading for anybody who's
listening um the crazy thing about to me
about this talk is like this is still
the stuff that we're talking about today
like and this was 5 years ago right yes
it's still applicable yeah like I find
bugs like like sometimes I need to go
back to those slides because I find bugs
for those things exactly they have
extremely long lifespan those blog posts
I'm surprised myself that it's like
still working and this is something
that's really I think a key listen and
also help helps for your for your brand
as well fron is that fron was was
talking about this stuff not not only
doing this stuff but talking about it
publicly in 2018 five years ago and I we
talk about post message still being an
underserved technology even to this day
so keep an eye on anything fronze
releases because it it will very likely
be applicable for the future um uh so
talk to me a little bit about uh app
cach and and service worker stuff and
then um in conjunction with that the
beauty of the synergies between cookie
stuffing and and these Technologies yeah
so I think the the the the interesting
part with the app cach uh that that
happened there there were there were
many many fun things with it but H my
aspect of it was that I had uh really
old Dropbox account and the old Dropbox
account were like grandfathered
into a place where you could actually
host websites on on Dropbox user
content.com H and you and if you created
a new Dropbox account back then you
couldn't really run your own like you
couldn't render HTML pages and stuff but
if you had a legacy Dropbox account you
could but it was very limited into what
you could actually uh trigger with it or
like get it to to um render um and I
came to the conclusion that like what
can I do with an xss or running an xss
on on Dropbox user content and I I
remember I was talking with Matias then
and like what can we do like can we do
something and we came to the conclusion
like Okay cookie stuffing we can
so you can make it like unable to
actually load because you're filling up
the cookie jar so much so when you're
making a request later on it will fail
so so question here so essentially what
was happening is you were able to host
your uh you know attacker controlled
content on a domain with with other
attack you know victim content on on
that same domain right yeah exactly what
happened was you got like a user
directory on Dropbox user content that
you could host data on
uh and then you could uh I think it was
that I can see it now and I I'll
reference it it's slide 15 for any of
those of you that are following along
here um you know he's got dld Dropbox
userc content.com you and then the user
ID and then wherever you would update
stuff and you got the xss not by
uploading an HTML file but by using SVG
right well I think it was an XML XML XML
you're right you're right yes XML yeah
so that was the thing uh everything else
was like you know getting downloaded and
position attachments H but that was the
way but but if you had a new Dropbox
account you would never get the URL to
to you Dropbox user user content it was
only the Legacy Dropbox account that had
that feature enabled um so that was the
you know the the weird part first with
with having that so we knew that we
could do cookie stuffing and what would
happen then if if somebody else sent a
link that would like 404 and or four of
four of
five or something I or
five 411 I think maybe actually yeah so
so that concept of of um cookie stuffing
I learned that from from you and from
file descriptor and and so I'm it file
descriptor that that I learned it from
it was from I was gonna ask where did
you get that knowledge and of course it
goes back to another Legend file
descriptor yeah file descriptor man and
and the funny thing with this bug was
that I think Matias was the one men
we're back to F scriptor so yeah he
mentioned appcash and I started reading
up on what appcash was doing and Matias
as well and we started like playing with
that and realized that we could you know
host reference a manifest into in the
XML file that manifest would then be
loaded and that manifest could be like a
regular text or whatever sure and that
text could contain and say that if if
you're unable to reach this website you
should have a fallback your fallback
page of this and that sure because the
whole app cach thing was based on you
running an app and you're going offline
with your cell phone so you need to if
you reload the page you can still visit
it this is crazy and absolutely crazy
and what happened was that we realized
that in our user path we could put an
HTML file or an XML file and we could
say that this is the one that should be
loaded if you can't reach the website
and then we realized okay does the
cookie stuffing result in this thing and
it turns out that yes so we cookie
stuffed and made sure that if you
clicked on any other link we would just
steal the URL and then steal the the
page of that signed URL ourselves that's
amazing but the weird part of was that
when we did this blog post I don't know
exactly date wise so our bug to Dropbox
was here and then here yeah and then
file descriptor comes out with a talk H
explaining this bug and we were like but
we what we what so that that was when we
wanted we got the Dropbox uh bug
published so we could show that we also
figured this out that's crazy uh and and
so so he actually did a talk on I think
on OAS OAS talk or or something else but
and so we came to the same kind of
conclusion uh which was great so I
wanted to like highlight that that like
sometimes people can like figure out the
same kind of things at the same time uh
and as you mentioned like there's like
the new thing I think I mentioning it as
well like service workers was a was a
like a a replacement for appcash but
back then I think it was like very hard
to like get a a service worker to work
because yeah you needed to have like a
specific header on the service worker
file to allow it to run as a service
worker and there were a lot of like if
this and that that that had to work uh
to make it actually exploitable it it
seems like there's there's definitely
been some change in that area now and so
um you know I've definitely seen service
workers used in in lots of different
different contexts I believe you and I
always have to you know go back and look
at it but I'm not 100% sure but I I I'm
99% sure that service workers can be
installed without a header now and the
header that if you do Supply an HTTP
response header what that will allow you
to do is reassign the uh the root path
the the the um Authority for that
service worker so if you you know even
though you're installing the service
worker at like sljs sjjs or whatever or
swjs um then then you know you normally
just have Authority for the sljs
directory but if you're able to serve
that service worker allowed I think
header um then you can get uh and say
Hey give it permission to slash then you
can now affect all the resources
everywhere um and it's it's such an
interesting technology especially when
you pair it with something like uh
subdomain take over or or um you know
file upload because you can gain sort of
sort of a persistence in the browser as
well um using service workers and and um
you know that that ex we've seen this
also with truffle security released a a
tool called of course I'm not sure if
you've seen it France but it's it's um
it uses a service worker in the
background to uh gain more time to be
able to attack different um websites
that have
configurations even if you just visit
the page for just an instant you know so
there's so many um I think
applicable you know exploitation
scenarios for service workers um that
that we we got to keep our eye on
because they they have tremendous impact
yeah no and I agree but like I I guess
the core concept first is like you need
to have an xss to begin with yes and and
then you probably need to have arguments
on why that exist wasn't important in
the beginning and I guess like storage
like a bucket storage is a is a is a
good argument on like an xss there
doesn't do anything but if you have
persistence you can like show and I
think that was what the the the bug
showed was like it's a Sandbox domain it
doesn't have any impact but you have
persistence and and and that's the way
to like gain access to other URLs and
stuff I just thought about something
France you know one of the things we're
going to talk about a little bit later
assuming we don't have to cut for time
is this middleware
misconfigurations that you you talked
about so what if we change that right
like we we changed the M middleware
misconfiguration um and and so now we we
can use that to hit a different bucket
on the so just to be I'm going to give
the tldr of the of the middle wear Miss
configuration thing if you if you
essentially with some enginex
configurations if you hit it if you put
a bunch of Escape characters you know um
new lines and stuff like that in the URL
and then have some specific proxy pass
rules
um then you will be able to re rewrite
the rest of the request and hit other S3
buckets or other backend entities host
your own content B exactly so what if we
we chained that with service workers
right um where you could then hit your
own S3 bucket and an issue but I'm
wondering I mean you still have stored
stored xss I guess like somebody needs
to visit your url still and and that one
would still make you host whatever
content you want on that website so the
but the the thing you're gaining is the
P the the persistent thing that you can
actually make it load but they still
need to visit it once can you can you
I'm wondering though can
you set response headers in S3 yeah it
depends if it's S3 website you can some
of them uh but I mean you could also if
it's S3 website you can still redirect
it to whenever like and depending on
like
the CSP for example you can still
redirect it elsewhere I don't know if
that helps you though no no because what
I'm thinking is like wouldn't it be cool
if we could insert some some new line
characters overwrite the the backend
bucket right have the bucket serve a a
service worker and then insert the
service worker header to slash so now so
that we we we gain you know that service
worker Authority um and get xss stored
xss on every single page that the user
visits in the browser I think that could
be really cool I mean S3 website would
allow you to do this if it's if the S3
website uh is if it's proxying you to S3
website and you can inject something to
modify what bucket it's going to serve
as a website you can inject whatever
head guess it depends on the host
because I wonder I wonder if if we are
hitting so let's say they're sending a
request to you know whatever. s3. Amazon
aws.com and then we overwrite the host
header on that I wonder if it uses that
same load balancer Orin IP for you to
insert a header to hit S3 websites like
if you if you put in it doesn't okay no
h S3 website is also quirky because it
only responds on HTTP and not htps oh
what uh I have no idea why I think it
has something to do with like you're
supposed to put it behind something else
kind of cloud front or whatever but so
they they don't have the same load
balancer in you can't really get to S3
website from S3 as far as I know weird
yeah that's that's definitely it's very
isolated it's like a totally it's like
an overlay over S3 it's like S3 website
is like its own thing that renders
whatever you want basically yeah well
definitely have to research that a
little bit more in dep the the other
area that I was thinking that this could
be interesting is with crlf injection uh
into the response headers right if you
can do response
splitting assign the service worker
allowed header then you can make a
service worker out of the response
plating yeah sure that would be pretty
you need something to load it I mean you
could probably make two crlf one crlf to
load a fake document and one crlf that
loads a fake service worker with the
Heather to install it absolutely that
should work yeah sure that's that's
that's some good that's some good [__]
right there um that's fun then you get
persistence yeah huh I'm just I'm
thinking all the possibilities can see
the gears turning in as soon as he hangs
up he's going he's got three programs
he's going to go
look then you and then you can probably
you know escalate it to you know steal
access tokens and stuff and yeah I mean
U you can probably do things with that I
guess and it it makes it a lot
more it makes it I
mean it's a little bit interesting right
because technically what that could
result in then is we could get plain we
could leak the user's plain text
password without user interaction right
because like like you said what what are
we actually what we what do we actually
gain from this because at that point if
we have stored xss right then we can
just open up whatever Pages we want in
an iframe and then do whatever we want
right and do whatever yeah but but one
of the things that we can't do is is
without more entry user interaction is
leak the user's plain text password
assuming they don't have any crazy thing
but but due to the persistence you can
uh you can get them to yeah sure which
which really escalates pretty much
any and then I guess it's a reflected
more than a stored but you turn it into
more of a stored a client side stored a
client side stored xss Cent side that's
that's really interesting and then and
then this this is a really good um atto
mechanism because some especially if you
then proceed to cookie bombb like a a a
specific path that that issu use you
know an off token or something like that
it forces the user to to clear their
cookies and reof the next time that they
they go into the application and at that
point if you've got the service worker
you can hijack the P the plain text
password yeah we this is this is some
good I didn't get you on this podcast
more often for this is great no no no
this is really good okay so um wow as
much as I would like to sit there and
just uh think on that for the next
little while let's let's try to keep
rolling um
it's probably a sin but I'm going to
skip this whole uh section on um S3
policies and Cloud policy uploads which
is a really awesome part of of the
attacking modern web Technologies uh
talk and I'm going to jump to something
that we've talked a little bit more
about on the podcast uh often which is
um the the post message stuff um so
uh how did you because I once again
you're one of the one of the first
people that I you know sort of
introduced me to post message stuff yeah
where where did you how did you come up
with this and then what what was it like
you know sort of seeing this did
somebody else's research spur this
thought in you or was it just how does
this work sort of that's that's a really
good question do you remember I guess
the first question no I I don't I I
actually don't 100% remember where I
think I think like this I think there
were examples of vulnerable cases
already like I wasn't the that you explo
it uh but I started to so I think I did
a lot of focus back then on I think it
was Dropbox maybe yeah and I think it
was so it was also like payment
providers there was something because
payment providers tend to do a lot of
and you had to talk yourself about it
yeah yeah and and what happened was that
there was a as a as a huge amount of
payment providers that started moving
over to post message and you always had
a really hard part finding all the post
message listeners so as I did back then
I was discussing with Matias like what
how how do we figure these things out
and and we came to the conclusion that
like okay probably an extension and then
I sat down and wrote a bunch of like you
know inside eye frames deep you know uh
message that that get listeners that get
triggers by actions and and a lot of
different I think it's still in the
repository there's like an example. HTML
with a bunch of listeners and and just
to like try to figure out what we can do
about it and I I I made my first uh
version of the of the extension and like
okay this will be usable like oh just
the number even though you have like
five ey frames deep a listener the
number counter on the post message
listener Chrome extension still you know
increase uh versus looking at the The
Source events Global events and you only
see the if frame you're currently
selected yeah I was like this is a
terrible functionality uh so I made my
first version of this and I I talked
with the Google team because I told them
like why can't you just like I don't
want to start building an extension like
can't you just fix so you can see all
the listeners in all ey frames yeah and
they're like no this is how it's
supposed to be and blah blah blah
it's terrible and it's something
something that I talked about in my talk
as well but like yeah you got to do your
D in in you still even have to do your
due diligence to go and show where all
of the you know to to go sus all of the
listeners because something may not be
utilizing that listener right so in that
case it won't show up in post message
tracker so you've still got to go
through and do it one of the and you
know it's my fault is as well because I
haven't contributed to that nice private
repo you put me on for for post TR but I
think it would beol to to add a a line
that that shows every time a post
message tracker is registered and where
it's registered so so you you know just
like you get a request where you know
you get a log in your console when it
gets sent through um when a post message
is sent through you can also get a log
when one is registered so you can know
okay well the you know
my uh child Windows third if frame has
registered a launch a listener that that
could be really cool because that attack
surface is all over the place like you
mentioned absolutely and and I would say
the most common ones I found nowadays
are the ones not initiated from from
start but by action yeah so they they
just because you so I have an example in
one talk I did on in Amsterdam for like
a live hacking event basically what
happened was that when you clicked on
upload document there was a listener
started at that action and then you
could do do whatever you could basically
read whatever document you uploaded you
could read it from the sandbox uh but
but so there's a bunch of those like
action-based listeners that gets
triggered by things and what I've seen
late like lately also and I think one of
the biggest tricks that up my sleeve
with the postmessage listener was the
unpacking of the rappers yeah uh so
basically everything is wrapped through
New New Relic or roll bar or there's a
bunch of those but and jQuery also has
its own wrapper but the way of figuring
out how to bypass the wrapper and then
go directly to the function so you can
get like the real function that is
actually being triggered that was I
think the the Golden Nugget in in the
extension that is that that was really
helpful and what I've seen lately now is
like people using message ports which is
like an addition to to post message
where you send an initial post message
with a port and that Port can then be
you know you can Shuffle that Port
between if frames uh but the one having
the port is the one getting the messages
yeah dude I'm so glad you mentioned that
cuz I just found my first you know bug
using message ports in a live hacking
event maybe well I won't say exactly
when because because that'll give it
away but but within the past year right
um and and it was uh it was very
interesting and I think one of the
things that that was crazy there is it
it sometimes people will just get a port
and then they'll just shove data into it
without doing you know or origin checks
or anything like that too so exactly you
know it actually even creates more
complexity and more room for
vulnerabilities when when you're
utilizing the message Port stuff yeah
and it's fun because you can you can
have a message Port from one little
iframe and if you get hold of that
message Port you can take it into a
different iframe and then the the the
window thinking it sends sends it to the
I frame is actually sending it cross
domain somewhere else so that message
Port can be you can juggle that message
Port wherever you want which is kind of
funny that it's like just a connection
it's basically like a a socket that you
can that shuffles data it's I'm also
kind of surprised that we haven't seen
more post message based tooling out
there like maybe I'm just naive but your
post message tracker is pretty much the
only extension that I've seen that that
does anything like this so um one thanks
for doing that because otherwise you
have no introspection I I use it every
day myself it's my the only probably
extension I use myself and every every
day I'm looking at it so it's like I'm
that it's a good example of like writing
something that would you would use
yourself yeah and it's 100% like that
like it doesn't go a day without me
looking at I i' kind of like also to
just to highlight you
know the importance of understanding
browser mechanics and stuff like that so
let's say for example you
you you know post message stuff was just
coming out or something like that right
and you go to a page and you see a an
iframe open up or or not an if frame a
popup you know open
up and it does something and then it re
you know that change somehow seems to
appear back on the on the original
window right and you don't see any HTTP
requests so it's not pushing it out to
the server and not coming back right so
you're like wait a second how the heck
is this working because if you have a an
understanding of browser mechanics you
you know you need you need some sort of
reference to pass it and that sort of
thing same origin kind of works still
yeah same origin is fine for that yeah
so it's it's important to understand you
know if it's happening cross origin like
that you can't just you know say parent
you know or opener dot you know window
you know whatever and just Define
variables or trigger callbacks in the
parent window if it's cross origin so so
having the a strong understanding of
same origin policy having a strong um
understanding of of um window references
you know that those sort of things are
essential to be able to identify these
sort of issues um for sure as the
technology evolves absolutely and I
think I one one thing that I I I did
some talks on it but I think
is there will be a lot more bugs on it
it's it's client side race conditions
with post message I I think that's I
think I was early on with it uh but I
think that there are much more places to
investigate that might be similarly
vulnerable to it I I don't have so I've
got a couple client side raise
conditions um in place um bugs that I
found and I'm actually doing some
research on them right now uh which I'll
share with you after this after this
chat um and maybe we can collab on it
because uh the implications of it are
pretty gnarly um but uh it's I need to
do what you did with OA 30 dancing and
just like you know work through all the
the work with all the pathways to it but
yeah I mean there there's so many things
that can be said about that one piece
that is not super relevant to the to the
um to the bug that the or to the
research that I'm talking about is the
the concept of client side race
conditions via post message when um one
of the people is using json.parse
so the thing about json.parse is that it
it when you're parsing that that Json
dat from a string back into a Json
object that takes
computational power to to load up all
those objects right so I had a scenario
when I was getting a post message at two
different windows at the same time right
and I needed to be so this window was
relay the first window that would
received the post message was relaying
it to me the attacker but then that
first window would respond to the post
message and set some configuration
settings right so I had to receive it
you needed a message to be first but you
also needed to read it faster than the
other exactly so the first the first
window that received it was using Json
par yeah string matching I guess exactly
I used I used just substring right to
extract this this variable that I needed
to send the message and was able to win
the race back to the first window that's
awesome and and so uh that's a that's a
cool little little TI those things are
are beautiful Json parse is a little bit
um
computationally also also I think like
the whole concept of
uh object like arbitrary objects I know
F scriptor made one of those using blob
yeah uh but there there are a bunch like
you can send a regx object yeah H and
and so there's a bunch of these like if
this is not a string kind of bugs that
you can find just because you're sending
a completely different object with post
message uh I think it's like file blob
regex there's a bunch of more that you
can uh you can send over wow I didn't
know that actually I got to look into
that and I know that some some providers
have implemented Frameworks where like
serialization and deserialization
Frameworks that just make my life
terrible they are crazy I know I know
exactly what you mean I've seen those as
well it takes a lot lot of time but
sometimes in those cases I I rather look
for the the syns first exactly or like
like is is it even you
know time to go down this path ex no
totally those are tricky I agree wow um
all right moving along I'm going to I'm
going to hit this next one pretty
quickly but I will say for any of you
that are are aspiring to be live hacking
event participants uh this talk by by
frons uh live hacking like an MBH a
walkthrough on methodology and
strategies to win big uh is an amazing
talk that talks about the live hacking
event experience and how to do well at
live hacking events um so we talk about
a lot of this stuff as well also let me
just say uh as of this past Vegas I have
been uh what is it deeded unseated as
the as tied for the most mvhs and now
fron has taken back his rightful TI
title as um you know MBH master of sorts
so I will get that back frons give give
me some time at some point at some point
I guess uh but this this you know this
talk goes through essentially uh the
hacking event flow and and actually some
of the OG live hacking event flow where
you would like you know have to use
Bounty please which is a a uh tool that
FR wrote to automatically submit all
your bugs in the beginning what a crazy
time man where you would just not where
you would like get if you didn't get
your bug in fast enough it was just
there was no Bounty like what the heck
no exactly I think I think it was also
you got duped because if someone posted
it before you didn't have a dup window
basically yeah it's crazy so yeah it was
It was kind of weird it like
incentivized building those toolings uh
for sure but I know people I I think
there have been live hacking events
lately also needed like that needed to
get in things quick so i' I've gotten
request to like like reignite that
project man because like and and I think
it's also to be honest because a lot of
people tend to write markdown reports
themselves first and then trying to like
get it in squeeze it into the the Bounty
platform so for those of you that my
favorite part about Bounty pleas by the
way is that it's all written in bash
yeah okay yeah I love bash damn I write
everything in bash yeah so I I was gonna
ask that same question Joel like dude
why do you write everything in bash like
like pipelines man you can it's like a
functional functional language because
you can pipe everything through
everything like it's it's like that's
where python py py python script into
some other python I mean like but but
now you like your whole script is based
on piping data through you know
conversions and and things so I think I
think it's just uh my mentality is not
like this is a script and this is a
pipeline with the script it's more like
my script is my pipeline or often I
think it's like an organic thing of like
my my my script is becoming it's
becoming a script because I used a
pipeline and now I'm like so I think
it's just my mentality of like that's
and I think I I tend to use it so much
also because it's like it's goes so fast
on building it yeah uh you know we we
we'll roll away we'll we'll let you
we'll let that fly we'll let that slide
no worries um and and we'll I wanted to
talk to you about collaboration in live
hacking events and I want to read a
quote from um the the this article and
you give a lot of great advice uh in
this article or in this um in this slide
deck about um essentially doing the work
that other people aren't willing to do
um focusing on the boring stuff and and
you know configuring all the things that
other hackers won't configure that's the
way to get the big bounties and the way
to hit sort of untapped attack surface
and that's great so I wanted to shout
that out but I also wanted to talk about
this section where you said uh you're
were talking about teaming because
teaming is something that we talk about
in critical thinking a lot Joel and I
Joel is one of the the few people um
actually one of the only people I think
that I ever done s in my opinion
successfully done a a collaboration with
over the past five years where it was a
full from the beginning to the end
collaboration right yeah um and I think
that's because I've been burned a little
bit in the past on large teams um and
and that that is what it is everyone
needs to have that learning experience
but I get a little bit of a bad WAP for
being anti- collaboration now I'm not
anti- collaboration by any stretch um
but you give some really great advice
here so let me read that with regards to
teaming team up with someone that one
will put similar effort into as you two
might know stuff you don't three helps
you cover more attack surface four you
can communicate with and brain stream or
brainstream uh brainstorm and then you
say both right exactly uh if you look at
uh freaking matias's DMS it might be
seem more of a brain stream than a
brainstorm I mean it makes sense brain
stream also um and then you say keep
keep teams small two to or if three or
more effort will differ allow splitting
differently for two people 50% is always
the simplest so that was sort of like
the brain dump of of collaboration
wisdom you did back in the day do you
still hold to all that absolutely 100% I
think and I I think it's very
interesting also in terms of like where
uh when like I do try to collaborate
with new people all the time um and and
you know once or twice sometimes maybe
around one bug and sometimes maybe you
know during an event or during just a
Target sometimes even and I always come
to the conclusion that it's like a lot
easier to do it two people uh because
then it's it's much easier to you know
it's very simple than if if both are
collaborating then then the full team is
there but if you're three maybe two of
them are working together one night the
other one can't and like it's it it just
just after two it becomes like really
hard to align that everybody's doing
equal work because you do you don't want
to get end up in like me personally
would not like to end up in the in the
scenario where I get paid for doing
nothing uh and I hope that other people
don't feel great about that either it's
like because I wouldn't I I I sometimes
feel bad with one person when that
person is providing much more than I do
uh but I I at least try to put in the
trying to find things uh but so I I
struggle a lot with h you know often
with like I'm like I don't need to be
collaborator on this thing because I
didn't do anything that kind of
mentality uh myself so I really like I
enjoy people having the same kind of
mentality themselves uh and you quite
quickly notice the ones that don't
really care and like almost gets to
you know ride on a sandwich it's a
Swedish proverb but but like uh gets
gets to do things are getting paid for
not do what the kind of proverb is that
ride on a sandwich r on a sandwich it's
actually it's actually ride on the
shrimp sandwich what the freak yeah yeah
yeah it's like yeah I don't I I yeah
it's weird but yeah so it's I and and so
that's why like when you identify the
people that like kind of align with you
on those things it becomes so much
easier to like collaborate and like just
focus on the fun stuff which is the
hacking part and and try to you know
find the best way uh to escalate the bug
yeah I mean that's one of the things I
really love about live hacking events is
that I find that more often than not any
random person at a live hacking event
that I walk up to I'm able to almost
like jump the line and get to a
communication level that like it's very
hard to established with other people
just out out of the gate and part of
that I think is just that like we all
have a similar kind of technical
background we all have a very common
like base of knowledge about like web
security or just even just Security in
general and like the types of bugs and
stuff and if you can get past that and
just start talking immediately about
like technical problems and being on the
same page it helps so much with actually
making progress with bugs I see this all
the time with me and Justin uh co-ack
essentially where we'll sit down at a
live hacking event and maybe one of us
will drive and the other one's just
really just like sitting there like
looking like seeing and like the
communication like we don't even speak
in sentences it's just like what he'll
be like oh that's really it'll be like
yeah I mean have we tried doing XY like
and we don't even like we kind of just
like we're looking at the same thing
we're consuming the same thing we can
kind of jump through communication and
almost in shortcuts um and I really love
being able to do that when you get to
like more and more people that starts to
fall apart and it becomes less scalable
I think probably most you can do that
with isbe like people where you have
people hled around like throwing ideas
before you start to run into
communication problems not not even just
like the the like barrier to to
communication but just like too many
people are talking at the same time or
like there's too many ideas running
around there's or there's too many
perspectives where it's like we're not
you know like we're never really going
down a full path because somebody you
know if three people think one thing and
the other person is like ah but like you
know what about this thing and then you
get sidetracked so definitely does work
best with with two I think yeah for sure
and I I the one the the times we've been
for it has naturally become you know
pairs H so you have two and two that is
like very much line and we've had done
we have done some live hacking events
for people but sometimes in those like
you sometimes also like you need to be
prepared to have like very tough
discussion like if it goes well you need
to have tough discussions on like like
hey guys me and you know X put in a
little bit more time than you guys I are
you all like fine with us you know
getting a larger percentage of whatever
it is and and and those kind of
discussions and if you can't have those
or if they turn you know ugly then it's
going to be a really hard time to to to
collaborate in the future but if you can
have those great ones then it doesn't
you know the reason the reason I bring
this topic up often on the podcast is
because I want people to be aware of the
fact that there there are some sticky
situations you can get into with this
right so anyone going into collaboration
needs to know that there is risk and
there's reward um and and you need to be
ready to have these these conversations
and here's the other thing a lot of
people will take the high road and say
like you know it's it's it's just money
you know it's not a big deal but I found
that those people will Harbor
resentment they they'll they'll leave
that that that resentment in their heart
right right and that that's not that's
not sometimes without knowing exactly
sometimes without knowing and that
that's not helpful for the community you
know and and so no I think I I I think
it's absolutely important to like if you
can feel that you dare to have that
discussions with the people you
collaborate with that's a really good
situation to be in because if you feel
that you can't take that up uh then
maybe you should I don't know then it
then it becomes like if you if you feel
that like I will put that back even
personally like I will avoid not saying
anything even though I feel bad like as
you said like you would feel bad going
forward like it's much better to like
ease it up and say like hey guys like I
I put in a lot of time in this and so
did he or something can we do something
about it and let them you know see where
they are what they are suggesting or you
know maybe they are saying yeah we 100%
agree then okay then you have then you
you can align that and then everybody's
happy um these problem you don't really
have these problems when uh when you
don't find though that's true like these
are these are like the Happy problems
yeah it's good problems to have and and
it's really good to train yourself to
have those discussions because you might
get stepped on if not and that's not a
great feeling to have either so um so I
know some people are like trying to
measure how much work they put in
compared to each other and stuff but I
don't I don't think that's uh that's a
good way it's just going to get dirty
but but I I think it's it's all around
finding the people that you know are
putting in the time that you and you
need to try right you need to try with
with people and and collaborate and
sometimes you find those matches like me
and shs hadn't uh collaborated but we
did last year for my first time and and
like after that we've been collaborating
maybe once a month sometimes more and
it's like it's so easy to do it together
we're like and also like
him him in Australia like I have a bug I
go to bed I I write to him before I go
to bed like this is what I found I wake
up and he like I found it I was like but
like this is Magic like this is such a
good collaboration and and turning turn
a high into a crit just because like he
found something I didn't and that's just
the power of collaboration me Matias
does that every single day so it's it's
such a such a great thing to uh to be
able to utilize H yeah yeah I love that
about collaborating like often when I
find somebody who's who I collaborate
with really well together it's not like
um it's not so much like I I don't
really think about who's found what bug
or like how should this be balanced it's
like usually if it's going really well
it's that we're both frustrated about
like the same things and maybe like one
person finds something that's really
critical uh but it's it's never like
just like by themselves like in a corner
like you two have both been putting in
like a lot of the same amount of brain
effort and for me that's what really
matters is like like what you said in
your slide is like find somebody who um
contributes like a similar amount of uh
of like effort and and you know time and
that kind of stuff because it's not
really like how many bugs they're
finding it's like are you on the same
page are you both engaged at the same
level like does it feel like we're both
putting in the same amount of energy
because that combined energy will get
satisfying outputs for both people even
if you didn't like find the exact
payload or whatever like you were there
the whole time yes yeah exactly that's
exactly 100% that and also like I think
with with the whole collaboration thing
uh I mean sometimes it's it's like the
the wins you do together is it's like
they last much longer than winning
yourself like they do and it's not it's
absolutely not only money mattering like
it's it's actually like we did this
together we we we we spent this time to
like we we we did all these things and
that win is like so much bigger than
than doing for sure I you know Joel that
the one of the most um foremost times
that that we collaborated together that
we did a full a full split collab that
is that is one of my favorite life hack
events I've ever done and my I think I
was asked recently in an interview
what's your favorite hacking memory the
the time that shell popped was my my
favorite hacking memory so absolutely I
think I remember
this um yeah you guys were similarly
[Laughter]
tired okay so um I want so the
middleware everywhere and lots of
misconfigurations to fix blog post
phenomenal I think we're going to skip
it for now um we talked a little bit
about it in the you know when we were
talking about the service worker stuff
and we're going to jump right to um
account hijacking using Dirty Dancing
and sign in O flows want to get in some
technical details here first I just got
to say
I love this concept of breaking the
state intentionally right in in the oath
flow um could you give us a talk a
little bit about that technique and why
that's so helpful because I freaking
love
it yeah so to be honest when I found
that that it was a technique I kind of
like yeah obviously it is uh but I also
realized like there is not that many
things uh other than the post message
that would be relevant for doing that or
doing so because there's not that much
things other than post message today
that might leak your full URL so the
whole thing with with oath uh breaking
the state intentionally is basically
that you often have this state parameter
where combined with the code that you're
getting back and the whole idea with the
state parameter is is that it's first
initiated by the website that you're
trying to sign into and then the state
parameter basically just gets sent
through the the O Dan and then comes
back identical to what you send send it
the the website sent it as and if it's
matching then it will go through the O
flow so it's a fully the the whole
mitigation Factor here is that if if the
website itself decides on a state
specifically for this uh user it can set
the cookie or whatever to make sure that
it's the same state that comes back it's
actually a mitigation to PR vent you
know uh somebody to send you a link and
and get get you to to connect to their
attacker account or you know a bunch of
other sea surfish uh attacks with with
OAS uh but the funny thing is that the
whole implementation of validating this
state is happening before you acquire
the code which is like the best thing
for the attacker if you can leak through
your url if you can get the victim to
use your your state instead because then
you can just take everything the the
code will never be used because the
validation of St before and and then and
then you can take it and rerun the same
code and you know the original state
because you generated the original state
yeah yeah yeah yeah I regenerated it and
send it to the victim the concept here
is you've got an attacker he's
positioned in such a way that he can
redirect a victim somewhere so or send
the link to it send to them send the
link to VI and and um so they they
generate an oath flow URL that has a
state that only the attacker knows right
and he gives a different state to the
victim and when the victim goes through
and and tries to even maybe use exchange
that code plus the state for an an off
token once it bounces back from the O
provider that that will fail because the
state does not match the internal state
but and then the code is just sitting in
the fragment and then you can go and get
that code and exchange that code plus
the state that you know for the and I've
actually seen some scenarios with this
where when the oath flow fails it will
redirect to a different location right
and and that can expose you start site
for examp exactly that can expose that
data to more to more risks which is yes
so yeah and and the the the funny part
with the whole state thing is also like
you don't often times you don't because
there's a difference between if you get
a code back in O flow you need to get
the code to convert into an access token
and and most often you need to provide
what redirect you right
that was being used and if that redirect
is differing from the redirect U that
was actually being used in the a St you
might not get the access token but
breaking the state is like you're ending
up on the correct redirect U it's
there's like that validation is just
like completely avoided because the same
redirect U you will end up on the same
correct Place uh and and but but the
state is the only thing that's breaking
it a so it's it's actually like one of
the reasons why some of the parts are
automatable when it comes to Dirty
Dancing gadgets and things because what
you can do is like you can figure out if
there are listeners when you're
intentionally me like changing the state
in a Lo flow if there are listeners
somewhere in that you know coming back
on the error page you can like easily
figure out that something is that's awes
is there for investigation yeah so you
know we talked about the ups and downs
of of doing the research in this article
which is phenomenal yeah the other piece
that I wanted to talk about was subbing
the the response type the to
tokenid token or or ID token versus code
and how that affects how the redirect
URI is used could you talk a little bit
about
that sure I mean the the concept I found
was that there are certain transfer
mechanisms that the oath specification
tells you to use depending on what type
of data uh the oath provider is sending
back to the website side what that means
is basically like for example if you use
uh um if you want to get back an access
token the access token is never supposed
to be sent as a query parameter it's
actually supposed to be sent as a
fragment part of the URL and the reason
for that is basically that it doesn't
show up in Access logs on the website um
you can still reach it with JavaScript
so the website can still get it but it's
not leaked to access logs or anything
the fragment stays on the client side
and it's client side script that needs
to fetch it uh same thing happens with
ID token ID token is like a little bit
in little bit in between but it tends to
be more on the fragment side than than
on the on the query parameter side but
in addition to this you have response
modes and some of the response modes
will fail if you try if you try for
example to get like a a token and you
have a response mode query sometimes
response mode query
is is a thing then you should be should
getting an error you should you you can
get it through either through fragment
or uh it's called Web post or web
message I think uh which is like
actually sending data over through post
message uh it all depends on the on the
oath provider what they've decided on
being the response modes Apple made up
them their own uh there's also one
called form post where it's posting
submitting the the access token as as a
post request to the website and that one
is I think I mentioned it in the end as
a potential exploitation Factor because
uh Google has even though you have like
really locked up redirect uis on on
Google uh you can still enable a mode uh
with parameters that tells you that it
should post uh post the the data as as a
post request but then you can select
whatever URL on the website you want
even subdomains what uh so that one is
is ripe for exploitation I think that
one is not supposed to work as it should
uh I mention it because I wanted it to
be fixed and I think I I do still think
it's possible to to utilize it the thing
I found with it though it's like it's
really there you can talk about stars
being in line because you need something
that either reflects post
uh in a way that you can read it
somewhere else through post message or
whatever so because post data you can't
reach reach with JavaScript unless you
reflect it uh the other thing you might
be able to do is like is there somewhere
on this domain where you can get the
post data to be read and I talked with
one of the team in Google and he said on
Google there is one so you have
script.google.com which is like a script
Gadget there you can have a URL that can
receive a post request and you can read
the logs of it that's that's basically
but but they don't have OAS danc on
their own website so Google don't don't
have it for Google uh I haven't found an
exploit exploitable Place uh that can be
used to submit the post request where
you can later on read I got to go reread
that because that section seems so
interesting Joel I know that this
episode has gone long do you have to
bounce right now I do have to bounce
so I don't want to cut this short but
I'm going to let you I'm gonna have to
hop on and listen to the rest of this
the rest of this you know a lot stuff
but yeah we'll definitely we'll talk
about about this more um and you can go
back and review it afterwards because
there's going to be some good stuff here
I can tell already so PE Joel but yeah
it it was awesome talking talking with
you and hopefully you guys have a good
rest of your conversation um yeah no
that that sounds nuts and and I think
playing with those different types is is
really something that I haven't played
around with too much um and something
that I want to I want to look into
because the the impact to that is is
massive too if you are able to leak
those in any capacity one thing that I
was thinking about for the Post message
thing is like it's very rare but if you
could find a 307 open redirect as well
yeah you could hit exactly they would
move it it's extremely rare uh but it
might be like Mis configurations in
their you know load balancer kind of
things but it 37s are hard I'm I'm I'm
I'm collecting 307s man they're hard to
find if you do that or you know like
well I guess most of the
time yeah n because you couldn't really
do it with a u with a crlf either you'd
really need yeah you really need a 307
it's It's Tricky man it is it's super
hard that's so so um the redirect so you
said sometimes different response types
will have different places that they can
redirect to that's some like is that is
that accurate or no
um I mean that I would say that one is
an exception especially for Google uh I
I would say that they
are in some sense you're right
because what happens with the web
message or the post message uh response
type or response mode is that then any
page on that or because it needs to
normalize the origin right so the origin
turns into the domain and that means
that any page on on that origin can read
the message sent by post message so in a
sense yes the redirect U will change in
that sense because it will just be any
any page on the origin getting that
message um I'm not I'm not fully
wrapping my I don't think so but there
you also have a an attack Vector because
there's a bunch of post message
listeners that works as proxies uh what
happens is that when they get a message
they will relay that message to an
iframe for for example so if you can
chain the the oath web uh the oath web
message posting a message to one of
those relays uh that just relays it to
another iframe and then you can find
something on that origin of the iframe
then you can uh then you can also find
like that's another sort of Gadget you
could say um but you still need to find
something maybe it's a s like the Reddit
bug I had I saw quite similar yeah so
the Reddit bug was basically that the
they used the window name to transfer
data over to their sandbox uh and the
sandbox had a bunch of xss people knew
about it like long before you could
literally run your own Google analytics
on it uh so if I ran my Google no Google
tag manager and if I ran my own Google
tag manager I could run script on the
soundbox uh but but because they named
the window with the payload the the
payload was transferred down through
window name and then you can read the
fragment through window name yeah I we
mentioned a different one uh a bug sort
of similar to that um there was a report
that came out on pixiv uh hacker one
program which is uh essentially the
vulnerability was the the app allows you
to specify your own Google analytics
token yeah and and if you can do that
then you can leak all sorts of stuff and
and with that you could redirect um the
aoth code to that a page that was was
using that Google analytics token which
would allow you to to leak the content
so there's all sorts of ways through
stats there's all sorts of ways that you
can access that um yeah and and I think
this one this account hijacking VI Dirty
Dancing one I I it's it's a very long
one like you've mentioned you know
there's there you like to do long
writeups but this is something I'm going
to go ahead and reread after this EP
after this episode again because there's
so many pieces to this where um I mean
the the out of bound things they're
they're there's so many things that I've
forgotten like that that's not even it
to be honest it's not even post message
like imagine imagine just having a
Tracker service or something that you
can leak that that has some form of API
somewhere else that you can leak dat so
the the the the outof band Gadget is
like there's huge potential for research
there because what happens if you break
the state for example you end up on the
page it sends it over to tracking
service X and Y but that tracking
service has some form of you know
history or whatever not through post
message or anything but you can you can
just utilize the same API key or
whatever like there's so many things
there that lot of application Level
stuff as well you know that you can use
just because that that one could be sent
so deep into something else somewhere
somewhere and you can pick it up those
are the nice ones where you like you
sent the victim over there it does a
bunch of things and then you're sitting
here pulling an API and suddenly it
shows up API you know a code or an
access token and you can steal it from
there those are the most kind kind in
the way you describe it as well
beautiful that that that even shows a
little bit more to the fact that um you
know these things they take so much art
you know they and and it kind of goes
back to what we were talking about
earlier of like I want to find a bug
that I'm proud of and sometimes that
takes time you know and so spending time
looking at applications like you said
sometimes it's three days three or four
days before you find a bug and some I
think a lot of people newer to the
industry would really stress out about
that but if you put in the time and you
really understand all of The Fringe
application logic then you start to be
able to chain together crazy stuff like
leaking o tokens via application
functionality that you know log stuff so
it's definitely cool to see um last
section that I wanted to talk about
before I I let you go do you have time I
know we're over time okay sure sure was
hacking plus Parenthood so I I I wanted
to so you know you mentioned before
sometimes you got a week a week and a
half and then you never know what that's
going to look like with kids um yeah you
know I'm I'm thinking about starting a
family soon and I'm a little bit worried
about what it's going to look like to do
fulltime Buck Bounty and have kids
around do you do you normally hack from
your home do you normally hack from the
office do you have any general advice
about bug Bounty with kids I know that
that's a broad question but yeah it's a
broad question it depends on the age of
the kids I guess but I I would say like
this uh I I had I was lucky with my
first kid being a really good sleeper
that's awesome but so that helped me
that helped me hacking a lot during
nights H that that was also in the in
the time where I was like almost
addicted to it so I really had to I
wanted to put in that
time and I invested almost like sleep
hours just because I I I was like almost
yeah monomania kind of thing uh but but
then I think with my my second kid which
was not such a great sleeper I kind of
came to to the point where I'm like that
was also where when I was working all
like working bug hunting and having two
kids and then I like I had to remove
something out
to no no that what the work went out
door actually so H because I I I felt
that like I really want to continue
doing hacking and uh kids are going to
stay um but but so I I think one of the
one of the aspects of it was
that it helped me like what what
happened then was that I replaced my
working hours with hacking hours which
has always been like I've been scared
about it because I felt like the
funniest bugs I find is always three a.m
like that has been a mantra to me that
that's the way it is because my mind's
working in in you know in a weird way
during during nights uh so so but but
that has kind of shifted now when I'm
going deep diving and because it you
know you're spending like five days on
one specific functionality it doesn't
really matter if it's happening on night
and day because you're getting into that
zone regardless during during those
there's some maturing that's happening
here you know like probably you know in
the beginning I I very much had the same
experience I was like wow I'm very
addicted to this and I would easily say
okay let me not go to bed and let me go
and hack you know and and I feel like
that was pretty pretty and it did get
great results but I think it was
unsustainable for me in some capacity
yes and so I think as as you kind of
grow as a bug Bounty Hunter and and you
figure out you know hey maybe there are
different options for this it becomes a
little bit more sustainable would you
would you agree with that yes yeah I
agree and I think to be honest like I
still have this thing where I'm like oh
I need to this but what I've realized
also is like the worst thing that can
happen is that I stop hacking at the
time where I don't have anything to
continue with h that's that feeling is
the worst because it makes it really
hard to start doing it again because
you're like where should I go where
should I go so I realized like the best
way the best place I am is where I'm
like oh my God and then I'm like closing
down the computer and I'm like oh that
like the day after I will wake up the
earliest I will go like do all the
chores everything and then I go back to
it compared to like I'm empty what an
amazing tip that is that is something
that I've never out of all the things
you've said this this time I feel like
this little
tip is kind of crazy because like that's
so counterintuitive to me like no I I
wouldn't want to give up right as I'm or
like stop right as I'm about to find
something but if you do you're so
motivated to come back and everything
else just seems to it becomes so much
easier to do like the chores or the
waking up early because as soon as your
eyes open in the morning you're like
wait I got to I got to try it you know
and so that's that's amazing and then
you you get like so I I really want to I
always want to find the place where I'm
like oh I I mean I understand like if
you're in the middle of like popping a
shell like oh yeah plus there's dupes
and stuff like that too you know yeah
but suddenly like you see an error
message that stands out or something
like like ooh like that's when I close
my computer that that's when because I'm
like okay I have something for tomorrow
it's it's almost like it's night here I
I will focus on something else but there
is something here and I have a huge
attack surface tomorrow that I can you
know H squeeze and and Fiddle around
with uh but but so that it's a it's a
very short amount of time where I have
the ability to like stop doing it
because I can continue and I will get to
a point where I'm like it's 5:00 a.m.
and I'm going to you know take the kids
school and and I'm going to be terrible
tomorrow and I've been there 100 times
but I'm I've realized also like it it
takes time to realize that okay I have a
short time span here where I'm like okay
I can get a good amount of sleep uh but
I will have some really fun days
tomorrow or Fun hours tomorrow to play
with dude that's but yeah it's it it
takes it takes it takes practice
practice and it takes self control and
it takes discipline you know and and for
sure like there the longer longer I'm in
this in Industry you you kind of see how
all this sort of becomes an art um you
know managing your your creativity and
your and your um you know it's similar
to painting I guess yeah and and and so
any any techniques like this which can
allow you to maintain that
creative um that Creative Energy that
creative motivation very important I
think France dude this has been an
amazing podcast thank you so much for
coming on here and sharing all the
wisdom which you've had over the over
the over the years of of doing bug
Bounty do you have any anything you want
to shout out or any socials you want us
to advertise at the end of
this no uh I mean shout out to my to my
collaborators that I often collaborate
with shs Al Brun um Frederick sitting in
the office behind me
um I'm having fun Peter as well a new
collaborator I haven't done anything p4g
dude awesome um that was that was uh a
great collab SC we're trying we're
always you know poking at each other I'm
going to stop you there because I I know
I know the I have so many I can
experience of like um you know you're
trying to think about like a I got to
think of all these people that I'm sure
there are many more you could list but
um yeah fron Rosen everybody uh you can
find them at Twitter pretty much
everywhere as fron Rosen just write out
the name and then definitely what we're
going to link down in the description
all the detectify blogs and stuff like
that which contain all the awesome
content from uh this episode in in more
depth so fron thank you so much man
thank you thank you by bye